can't.
できません。
Academia Sinica's August knowledge feast lecture begins.
中央研究院の8月の知識の饗宴講義が始まります。
Please ask Vice President Chen Jianren to host for us.
陳建仁副総統に司会をお願いします。
It's gentlemen. Good night, everyone.
紳士諸君、おやすみなさい。
Today I am very glad that we were able to invite you from the branch of our Central Research Institute
本日は、中央研究所の支部から皆様をお招きすることができて大変うれしく思います。
very distinguished scholar
非常に著名な学者
Teacher Cai came to give us a very important speech
蔡先生がとても重要な話をしに来てくれました
The case before Teacher Cai started to give a speech
蔡先生がスピーチを始める前の件
I said I need a brief introduction
簡単な紹介が必要だと言いました
Mr. Cai, he graduated from our National Taiwan University with a bachelor's degree and a master's degree.
蔡氏は、国立台湾大学を卒業し、学士号と修士号を取得しました。
After graduation, he went to Carnegie University in Pennsylvania to complete his Ph.D.
卒業後はペンシルベニア州のカーネギー大学に進学し、博士号を取得しました。
After finishing his Ph.D., he continued to study at the University of San Diego in California, USA.
博士号を取得した後も、米国カリフォルニア州のサンディエゴ大学で学び続けました。
Three and a half years as a postdoctoral researcher
博士研究員としての3年半
Then came back to Taiwan, back to Taiwan in 1994
その後台湾に戻り、1994年に再び台湾に戻りました。
After returning to Taiwan, the performance is quite outstanding
台湾に戻ってからのパフォーマンスは非常に優れています
Teacher Cai's research in the part of molecular biology
蔡先生の分子生物学の研究
The research done is published in the world's leading journals
行われた研究は世界の主要なジャーナルに掲載されています
As scientists, there is a journal in
科学者として、
Nature is already amazing
自然はもうすごいです
Then he not only has Science on NATURE
そうすれば、彼は自然に関する科学を持っているだけではありません
this is a scientific journal
これは科学雑誌です
The natural journals I just talked about, the scientific journals
先ほど話した自然誌、科学誌
Cell Journal
セルジャーナル
ShareJournals
ジャーナルを共有する
So if a person can have three papers
つまり、人が 3 枚の紙を持っているとすると、
Publishing in these journals is already amazing
これらのジャーナルに掲載することはすでに素晴らしいことです
but more importantly
しかし、もっと重要なことは
in recent years
近年では
This teacher Cai's laboratory published papers
この蔡先生の研究室は論文を発表しました
He has six papers
彼は6つの論文を持っています
It is a better journal abroad
海外ではもっと優れた雑誌です
he will have some recommendations
彼はいくつかの推奨事項を持っているでしょう
Unit's website
ユニットのウェブサイト
That's called Faculty 1000
それはファカルティ1000と呼ばれます
He has six papers recommended in Faculty 1000
彼はFaculty 1000で6本の論文を推薦しています
This is not easy
これは簡単ではありません
So today Mr. Cai can come to give us a speech
今日は蔡氏が講演に来てくださることになりました
it's an honor for all of us
それは私たち全員にとって光栄なことです
Teacher Cai's absorption of nutrients in this plant
蔡先生がこの植物から栄養を吸収する様子
and interest transmission
そして利息の伝達
There is a very in-depth study of this
これについては非常に詳細な研究があります
In addition to publishing his research results in very important journals
彼の研究結果は非常に重要な雑誌に掲載されているだけでなく、
other than what i just said
私が今言ったこと以外に
He also because of his research results are very good
彼は研究成果も非常に優れているので、
So it's a prize winner
ということで入賞者です
frequent prize winner
頻繁に賞を受賞している
He won the Outstanding Award of the Hot Pot Club
鍋クラブ優秀賞受賞
and academic awards from the Ministry of Education
文部省からの学術賞など
Then the Young Scholar Award of the China-Ireland Research Institute
その後、中国・アイルランド研究所の若手学者賞を受賞
just came back
ちょうど今戻ったとこだよ
are quite outstanding
非常に優れています
that's also important
それも重要です
That is to say, Mr. Cai is winning the prize
つまり、蔡先生が賞を受賞することになる
This is beyond count
これは数え切れないほどです
Also a very important thing is
また、非常に重要なことは、
He also trained many students
彼はまた多くの生徒を指導しました
Some students from his lab also came today
今日は彼の研究室の学生も何人か来ました
just had dinner with them
彼らと夕食を食べたばかりです
His laboratory has a characteristic
彼の研究室には特徴がある
boys are happy
男の子たちは幸せです
He has many hosts
彼にはたくさんのホストがいる
Many of them are just kidding
彼らの多くはただの冗談です
But this teacher Cai is very admired by the students
しかし、この蔡先生は生徒たちからとても尊敬されています
and loves coming to his lab
彼の研究室に来るのが大好きです
like this summer vacation
今年の夏休みのように
He has five undergraduate students
彼には学部の同級生が5人いる
to his lab
彼の研究室へ
Including those who have not yet come from Hong Kong
まだ香港から来ていない人も含む
So he seems to be quite famous internationally.
なので、世界的にはかなり有名なようです。
and highly valued
そして高く評価されています
then we are really happy
それなら私たちは本当に幸せです
Today we have a feast of knowledge in August
今日は8月の知識の饗宴があります
I can invite Teacher Cai
蔡先生を招待できます
come do it with us
来て私たちと一緒にやりましょう
so
それで
I think everyone will be rewarded with a speech given by
～によるスピーチは誰もが報われると思います
Then look at the title itself, it is already very attractive
それからタイトル自体を見てください、それはすでに非常に魅力的です
Right? The beauty and sadness of light fat
そうでしょ? 軽い脂肪の美しさと哀しさ
Everyone knows that Beauty and Sorrow is a famous novel
『美しさと悲しみ』は有名な小説であることは誰もが知っています
Everyone knows Japanese novels
誰もが知っている日本の小説
Then let's listen to how plants count
それでは、植物がどのように数えられるかを聞いてみましょう
There is also a memory map to let the content of the sales face inside
販売内容を内側に見せるメモリーマップも付いています
The content of sales color is very important for the growth of plants
販売色の内容は植物の成長にとって非常に重要です
then today we
それから今日私たちは
After listening to the speech, we believe
スピーチを聞いて私たちはこう信じます
There will be a deeper understanding of the beauty and sorrow of light fat
軽い脂肪の美しさと哀しさへの理解が深まるでしょう。
We'll cycle around at
でサイクリングします
around 8.5
8.5左右
Q&A for everyone
みんなのためのQ&A
If it's in the middle, we'll ask Mr. Cai
途中であれば、蔡先生をお招きします
Let's talk from the beginning to the end
最初から最後まで話しましょう
If we are comfortable, Tiger Claw will come to welcome Teacher Cai.
気が向いたら、タイガークローが蔡先生を迎えに来るでしょう。
Today I would like to thank the Vice President for his introduction
本日は副社長の紹介に感謝したいと思います。
Thank you for giving me this opportunity to chat with you
あなたと話すこの機会を与えてくれてありがとう
beauty and sorrow
美しさと悲しみ
what is its beauty
その美しさは何ですか
Well, here is a picture of the population of the whole world
さて、これは全世界の人口の写真です
You can see from 1800 years ago
1800年前から見ることができます
1800 to present
1800年から現在まで
The sudden increase in the population at this turning point
人口急増のこの転換期
Before 1940 to 1960
1940年以前から1960年まで
a big turning point
大きな転換点
that is now at this point
それは今この時点で
they estimated
彼らは推定した
If the current growth rate
現在の成長率だと
Our population will be as high as 16 billion
私たちの人口は160億人に達するでしょう
That's what it looks like if it slows down
速度が落ちるとこんな感じになります
hope to reduce
減らすことを望む
So what caused such a big turning point
では、何がそのような大きな転機を引き起こしたのか
some say there is no war
戦争は存在しないと言う人もいる
no war, yes
戦争はありません、はい
absence of war is an important factor
戦争がないことは重要な要素です
Another very important factor is
もう一つの非常に重要な要素は、
During this period a green revolution took place
この時期に緑の革命が起こりました
what is green revolution
緑の革命とは何ですか
The green revolution was an agricultural revolution
緑の革命は農業革命だった
it's not like
それはそうではありません
Our revolution is shaken and cold
私たちの革命は動揺し、冷たくなっています
So its de facto deadline is hard to set
したがって、事実上の期限を設定するのは困難です
But from 1940 to 1970
しかし、1940 年から 1970 年まで
This green revolution created
この緑の革命が生み出した
Saved hundreds of millions of people from starvation
何億人もの人々を飢餓から救った
It also created this opportunity to allow the world's population to rise
また、このことが世界の人口増加を可能にする機会を生み出しました。
Several important components of the green revolution
緑の革命のいくつかの重要な要素
One of them is the generation of high-volume new products
その 1 つは、大量の新製品の生成です。
This is the technique of Yu Zongxue
これが兪宗雪の技です
many new varieties
たくさんの新品種
There is also the establishment of an open system
オープンシステムの確立もある
Next is the modernization of management technology
次は管理技術の近代化です
There is also a very important factor
非常に重要な要素もあります
It is the use of fertilizers and sand insecticides
肥料や砂用殺虫剤の使用です。
Fertilizers are what we're talking about today
今日は肥料についてお話します
Sand insecticide also has its beauty and ugly
砂用殺虫剤にも美しさと醜さがある
not something we can talk about today
今日は話せることではない
Today we are talking about the beauty and ugly of fertilizer
今日は肥料の美しさと醜さについて話します
ok i believe here
わかりました、私はここを信じます
Many people have flowers in their homes
家に花を飾っている人も多い
Maybe they all went to Jianguo Flower Market to buy fertilizer
もしかしたらみんな建国花市場に肥料を買いに行ったのかもしれない
What is the composition of the fertilizer?
肥料の成分は何ですか？
one hundred percent
百パーセント
good egg zero leave
良い卵ゼロ休暇
Inside the egg is about two to four percent of the dry plant
卵の中には乾燥した植物の約2〜4パーセントが入っています
actually the most important
実は最も重要な
The ingredients are probably egg zero fake inside from
原材料はおそらく卵ゼロの偽物です
The highest content of zero, false
ゼロの最高含有量、偽
The sources of these three fertilizers
この３つの肥料の原料は
Zero and fake are probably obtained from minerals
ゼロと偽物はおそらく鉱物から得られる
only eggs
卵だけ
At present, it is artificially synthesized into the mass
現在では人工的に合成されて大量に作られている
That
それか
Why is egg fat important?
卵脂肪はなぜ重要ですか?
This is actually an experiment done in Rosenstadt, England
これは実際にイギリスのローゼンシュタットで行われた実験です
In fact from 1840 until now
実際には 1840 年から現在まで
they do different nutrients
彼らは異なる栄養素を提供します
Effects on Plant Growth
植物の成長への影響
Then when I first returned to Taiwan in 1994
そして1994年に初めて台湾に戻ったとき
Just ran to this Rosenstadt to visit
このローゼンシュタットを訪れるために走ったところです
That's because of the influence of a teacher over there
それは向こうの先生の影響です
a special technique
特別なテクニック
He can measure the cytoplasm
彼は細胞質を測定できる
What is the content of antiaciditis
抗酸炎の内容は何ですか
i thought wow amazing
すごいと思った
I hurried to ask him that I can not study
私は急いで彼に勉強ができないと尋ねました
so i went
それで行ってきました
Then he went and said do you want to go to this
それから彼は行って、ここに行きたいかと言った
take a walk inside the fuel
燃料の中を散歩してみよう
I didn't know then
その時は知りませんでした
this is such a historical thing
これはとても歴史的なことです
walk in that path
その道を歩く
It's walking in that stage of history
歴史のその段階を歩いている
then go here
それならここに行ってください
see this long-running experiment
この長期にわたる実験を見てください
what this experiment tells
この実験が何を物語るか
Tell us the importance of leading the armor
甲冑を率いる重要性を教えてください
this is a different year
今年は違う年です
1872 to 1881
1872年から1881年
or 1985 to the 90s
または1985年から90年代
You can see that nothing is added
何も追加されていないことがわかります
This yields 0.9
これにより、0.9 が得られます。
Here is 2.6
こちらが2.6です
there is a difference
違いがあります
why is it higher
なぜ高いのですか
This is the birth of new species
これが新種の誕生です
Therefore, the yield of new varieties is relatively high
そのため新品種の収量が比較的多い
that early agriculture
その初期の農業
just rely on the sky to eat
空に頼って食べるだけ
How much fertility is this soil corridor
この土壌回廊はどれほどの肥沃度があるのか
how much you eat
どのくらい食べますか
But then they knew
しかしその後彼らは知ったのです
If I add some nutrients
栄養を少し加えたら
If light adds zero heel armor
光がヒールアーマーをゼロにすると
increases its output
出力を増加させます
The current new varieties have no way to increase the zero price
現在の新品種はゼロ価格を引き上げる方法がない
But I don't add zero price
ただしゼロ価格は追加しません
Just add eggs and you will see
卵を加えるだけでわかります
The output can be doubled
出力を2倍にできる
That's of course the best case scenario
もちろんそれが最良のシナリオです
Egg zero price you give all
全てを捧げた卵ゼロ価格
Just like the fertilizer we bought at the Jianguo Flower Market
建国花市場で買った肥料のように
just look good
ただ良く見えるだけ
This one is actually the same idea
これも実は同じ考えです
but you can see the time change
でも時間の変化はわかります
Sure enough, after the green revolution, the output increased
案の定、緑の革命後、生産量は増加しました
They use some of the most popular
彼らは最も人気のあるもののいくつかを使用しています
wheat to grow such an experiment
小麦を栽培する実験
Then you can watch
そうすれば、見ることができます
this picture
この絵
Another thing to look at is
もう一つ注目すべき点は、
after adding zero and false
ゼロと false を追加した後
So add different amount of eggs
なので、卵の量を変えてください
Forty-eight kilograms of eggs are added here
ここに48キログラムの卵が追加されます
Then add one hundred and forty-four
次に、144を追加します
you can see that the yield increases
収量が増加していることがわかります
In fact, it is more obvious
実際にはもっと明らかです
We can use the following picture to see
次の図を使用して確認できます。
This is the different amount of eggs
こちらは卵の量が違います
Then its output increases
すると出力が上がります
Then actually this picture
そしたら実はこの写真
also explained a very important thing
非常に重要なことも説明しました
Increasing production can indeed
生産量の増加は確かに可能です
while increasing egg fertilizer
卵肥料を増やしながら
The number of eggs can indeed increase production
卵の数は確かに生産量を増やすことができます
but to a certain extent
しかし、ある程度までは
actually you are increasing
実際にあなたは増えています
did not increase production
生産量は増えなかった
this is actually
これは実際に
A branch of the Taiwan Council of Agriculture wants to tell the farmers
台湾農業委員会の支部は農民たちに伝えたいと考えている
Don't add too much egg fat
卵脂肪を入れすぎないでください
Then I'll tell you why you shouldn't add more lamp ash
じゃあ、なぜランプの灰をもっと加えてはいけないのか教えてあげるよ
In fact, the output is not
実際、出力はそうではありません
But for a farmer
でも農家にとっては
We see these small gaps
これらの小さなギャップが見えます
we don't feel that important
私たちはそれほど重要だと感じていません
But for farmers
しかし農家にとっては
he refused to post
彼は投稿を拒否した
that danger lowers production a bit
その危険により生産性が少し低下する
It must be added to the fullest.
最大限に追加する必要があります。
What about the lack of eggs?
卵不足はどうなるの？
the first time you can see the lack of eggs
初めて卵が足りないことに気づきました
Plants are of course small
植物はもちろん小さいです
Not only does it turn yellow when you first see it
初めて見たときは黄色くなるだけではありません
Then yellowing and what?
それから黄ばみとか何？
How do plants without eggs actually taste?
卵のない植物は実際にどのような味がするのでしょうか？
Astringent and light but very hard
渋くて軽いけどとても硬い
because it smells fishy
生臭い匂いがするから
Excessive fibrosis, not tasty
過剰な線維化、美味しくない
So vegetables must have a lot of egg fat
つまり野菜には卵脂肪が多く含まれているはずです
so fresh and sweet
とても新鮮で甘い
well , source of egg fat
さて、卵脂肪の源
Let's talk about the history of egg fertilizer
卵肥料の歴史について話しましょう
The earliest egg fertilizer was bird droppings
初期の卵の肥料は鳥の糞だった
really fun
本当に楽しい
This island is full of bird droppings
この島は鳥の糞でいっぱいです
This white thing is all bird droppings
この白いものはすべて鳥の糞です
You can see that the bird was full at that time
そのとき鳥がいっぱいだったことがわかります
You can't find an open space to occupy that dive level
そのダイブレベルを占めるための空きスペースが見つかりません
That's because the flock of birds live there
そこには鳥の群れが住んでいるからだ
Then come here again it won't rain
それからまたここに来てください、雨は降らないでしょう
So that guano is accumulating on that island
その島にはグアノが蓄積している
So start digging these
それで、これらを掘り始めてください
You see this is the port a ship is taking it out of
ここが船が出港している港です
From 1884 to 1990
1884年から1990年まで
rely on this guano
このグアノに頼ってください
But it will run out soon
でもすぐになくなってしまいます
then what should we do
じゃあどうすればいいのか
OK, the next step is to pick
OK、次のステップは選択です
Ore has a natural hydrating stone
鉱石には天然の保湿石が含まれています
called Soulpeter
ソウルピーターと呼ばれる
It is mainly Acid Acid
それは主に酸です
Where is it produced then?
それではどこで生産されているのでしょうか？
south american
南アメリカ人
Atagamasamo
あたがまも
Atacama
アタカマ
Dazer
デイザー
I write about South America here
ここでは南米について書きます
It's weird why I just wrote about Peru
なぜ今ペルーについて書いたのか不思議です
How about not writing a country here?
ここに国を書かないのはどうですか？
it's actually fun
実際楽しいです
This fertilizer saliva
この肥料の唾液
also sparked war
戦争も引き起こした
You can imagine it's mastering the source of that grain
それがあの穀物の源であると想像できます
it sparked a war of limestone
それは石灰岩戦争を引き起こした
Well, this summer actually used to be in
さて、今年の夏は実は
bolivia and peru
ボリビアとペルー
But where are the mining rights?
しかし、採掘権はどこにあるのでしょうか？
mining rights in intellectual
知的財産における採掘権
That is to say, mining technology
つまり、マイニング技術
Intellectual comparison, development is more advanced
知的比較、開発がより進んでいる
So it has mining technology
つまり採掘技術がある
So in fact, you can't step into other people's houses to pick them.
したがって、実際には、他人の家に足を踏み入れて拾うことはできません。
It's been a long time since the material was picked
素材を選んでからかなり時間が経ちました
just say it's mine
それは私のものだと言ってください
Of course such a precious mineral
もちろん貴重な鉱物です
The two countries fought against each other
その両国は互いに戦った
Played for four years, but was robbed by intelligence
4年間プレーしたが、知性を奪われてしまった
So that Dazer is now Intellectual
デイザーが知的になったということで
This Dazer is actually still picking
このDazerは実際にはまだ選んでいます
And it used to be the largest industry in intelligence
かつてはインテリジェンス分野で最大の産業でした
Intelligence is equal to relying on this to start
知性とはこれを頼りに始めることに等しい
feed more intelligence
より多くの知性を養う
Around 1912 was the peak time
おそらく1912年頃が最盛期だったと思われます
Then its total content was estimated to be about 920 at that time
当時、その総含有量は約920と推定されました。
Million tons
百万トン
At that time, I wanted to say that when I encountered this mine, I thought
あの時、この鉱山に出会った時、こう思ったと言いたかった。
It has been installed for 340 years and I can't finish it
340年間設置されているが、完了することはできない
Unexpectedly, I just said
思いがけず、さっき言いました
Because of the green revolution and then the demand for fertilizers increased
緑の革命とその後の肥料の需要の増加のため
this amount they say
彼らが言うこの金額
In fact, it's gone in about two or three years now.
実際、ここ2、3年くらいでなくなってしまいました。
So we must find other ways
だから私たちは他の方法を見つけなければなりません
well what method
さて、どのような方法ですか
synthetic
合成
good source of eggs
卵の良質な供給源
Where is the biggest egg
一番大きな卵はどこですか
inside the air
空気の中
79% of the air is eggs
空気の79%は卵です
but we can't use it
でも私たちはそれを使えない
what to do
何をすべきか
Fortunately at that time
幸いなことにその時は
there was a german chemist
ドイツ人の化学者がいました
Harbor
港
he invented
彼が発明した
use a
使う
high pressure
高圧
high temperature method
高温法
turn the egg into green
卵を緑色に変える
compression
圧縮
after fix
修正後
catalyzed by iron
鉄によって触媒される
let it produce an
を生成させます
this is harvard law
これはハーバード法です
this way
こちらです
Rescue the need for egg fertilizer
卵肥料の必要性を救う
well worth mentioning
言及する価値は十分にあります
Harvard law
ハーバード法
actually
実際
someone said
誰かが言いました
this is human
これは人間です
One of the most important chemical reactions in the history of development
開発の歴史の中で最も重要な化学反応の 1 つ
Because the egg on each of you
なぜなら、あなた方一人一人の卵は
The formation of most proteins exists
ほとんどのタンパク質の形成は存在します
Half of it came by this method
半分はこの方法でできました
They say this is the greatest invention
彼らはこれが最大の発明だと言う
Sure enough, he also won the Nobel Prize.
案の定、彼はノーベル賞も受賞しました。
Actually I just mentioned
実は先ほども言いましたが
He's a chemist, he invented this method
彼は化学者で、この方法を発明したのです
but industrialized him
しかし彼を産業化した
In fact, Bosch did it
実際、ボッシュはそれを行いました
So someone actually said that this method
それで、誰かが実際にこの方法を言いました
It should be a way for two people to cooperate
それは二人が協力する方法であるべきです
More controversially, Hoffer
さらに物議を醸しているのは、ホッファー氏
Hoffer gave him the Nobel Prize
ホッファーは彼にノーベル賞を与えた
He was given the Nobel Prize in 1918
彼は 1918 年にノーベル賞を受賞しました
the nobel prize
ノーベル賞に
It's actually kind of controversial
実はちょっと物議を醸しているんです
Everyone wants such a great invention
誰もがそのような偉大な発明を望んでいます
why no nobel prize
なぜノーベル賞が出ないのか
Actually he has another invention
実は彼には別の発明がある
very harmful to humans
人間にとって非常に有害です
He was the one who made the poison gas of the first world war
第一次世界大戦で毒ガスを作ったのは彼だ
So he was the poison gas of WWI
つまり彼は第一次世界大戦の毒ガスだった
He participated in the first generation of chemical warfare
彼は第一世代の化学戦争に参加した
a man full of tragedy
悲劇に満ちた男
his son, his wife
彼の息子、彼の妻
can't stand
我慢できない
How many people died by chemical gas and committed suicide
化学ガスで何人が死亡し、自殺したのか
So this is a half-baked scientist
つまり、これは悲惨な科学者です
He saved a technology that we humans are still using continuously
彼は私たち人類が今も使い続けているテクノロジーを救った
But he also made
しかし、彼はまた、
he does it for himself
彼は自分のためにそれをする
He famously said
彼は有名にこう言いました
He said a chemist was of the world in times of peace
彼は化学者は平和な時代には世界の一員だったと言った
Belongs to the country in time of war
戦争中は国のものです
so he thinks he's doing the right thing
だから彼は自分が正しいことをしていると思っている
anyway we have no way to evaluate this matter
いずれにせよ、この問題を評価する方法はありません
but you can know that
でもそれは分かるよ
This Bahafa has really caused the human population to
このバハファは実際に人類に次のような影響を与えました。
a reason for boom
ブームの理由
so until now
だから今まで
what i tell you is
私があなたに言うことは
light fat beauty
軽い脂肪の美しさ
Where is love?
愛はどこにある？
First, he consumes energy
まず、エネルギーを消費します
I just said that he needs high temperature and high pressure
彼には高温と高圧が必要だと言いました
Where do these high temperatures and pressures come from?
このような高温と圧力はどこから来るのでしょうか?
Of course, energy is needed to produce
もちろん生産にはエネルギーが必要です
What does this energy depend on?
このエネルギーは何に依存しているのでしょうか？
Powered by our world's energy
世界のエネルギーを動力源として
in fact they say
実際彼らは言う
The consumption of Harvard law
ハーバード法の消費
1% of the world's energy is consumed on this
世界のエネルギーの 1% がこれで消費されています
we also know
私たちも知っています
Energy is now becoming more and more precious
エネルギーは今、ますます貴重になっています
So the pressure is getting higher and higher
だからプレッシャーはどんどん高くなっていく
But the demand for light fertilizer is increasing every year
しかし、軽質肥料の需要は年々増加しています
Now it's about 90 a year
今では年間90件くらいです
Minion tons, million tons
ミニオントン、百万トン
Then it is estimated that it may soar to 140 or so in the future
将来的には140程度まで上昇する可能性があると推定されています
Just because we talked about the energy crisis
エネルギー危機について話したからといって
Energy It has such an energy-consuming reaction
エネルギー 非常にエネルギーを消費する反応です
so fat
とても太った
The price of fertilizers soars every year
肥料の価格は年々高騰している
Now increase by 20% to 25% every year
現在は毎年 20% ～ 25% ずつ増加
From here we can see
ここから見えるのは
before you planted crops
作物を植える前に
Three Biggest Investments
3 つの最大の投資
one is to buy fertilizer
一つは肥料を買うことです
buy more seeds
もっと種子を買う
Next is insect repellent
次は防虫剤です
in 2005
2005年に
For example, in the case of soybeans
例えば大豆の場合
Buying fertilizer is about 25%
肥料の購入は約25％
Then the seeds make up about 32%
種子は約32％を占めます
Then 92% of the investment in pest control
その後、投資の 92% が害虫駆除に当てられます。
By 2009
2009年までに
different species
異なる種
40% of the cost of fertilizers
肥料代の40％
So it's like saying you're going to spend
だからそれは費やすと言っているようなものです
40% of your fee
料金の40％
is to invest in the purchase of fertilizers
肥料の購入に投資することです
So the cost is getting higher and higher
そのためコストはどんどん高くなっています
That
それか
It's not the saddest thing
それは最も悲しいことではない
This is not the biggest sorrow
これは最大の悲しみではありません
money problems can be solved
お金の問題は解決できる
Energy problems can be solved
エネルギー問題は解決できる
can also be solved
も解決できます
The most unsolvable thing is the pollution of the environment
一番解決できないのは環境汚染です
what kind of environmental pollution
どのような環境汚染なのか
But there is only one problem
しかし、問題が1つだけあります
In fact, the fertilizer use rate of wet down is very low
実際、ウェットダウンの肥料使用率は非常に低いです。
can be used by plants
植物が利用できる
Most are exploited at 30%
ほとんどが 30% で搾取されています
Most of them cannot be used by plants
そのほとんどは植物には利用できません
How about using plants?
それでは植物をどうやって使うかは仕方がありません。
it will wash away
それは洗い流されます
that or it produces nitrous oxide
または亜酸化窒素が生成されること
This nitrous oxide is a ratio
この亜酸化窒素は比率です
we are all talking now
私たちは今みんなで話しています
that greenhouse gas
その温室効果ガス
Greenhouse gases talk about liquid nitrogen oxide every time
温室効果ガスについては毎回液体窒素酸化物について話します
nitrous oxide
亜酸化窒素
N2O is actually more nitrogen dioxide than CO2
N2Oは実際にはCO2よりも二酸化窒素のほうが多いです
Nitrogen is even more toxic
窒素はさらに有毒です
300 times more poisonous than a single greenhouse gas
単一の温室効果ガスの 300 倍の毒性
its effects can last
その効果は持続する可能性がある
and more serious
そしてさらに深刻な
this is a problem
これは問題だ
Another problem is that
もう一つの問題は、
Of course, the moisture absorption is 30%
もちろん吸湿性も30％です
others will be lost
他の人は失われるでしょう
Wash it away, where does it go?
洗い流して、どこへ行くの？
flushed into groundwater
地下水に流された
flushed to the river, flushed to the sea
川に流される、海に流される
What happens when it is washed into rivers and oceans?
川や海に流れ込んだらどうなるのでしょうか？
euoxidative
脱酸化的
Euoxidation means it has too much oxygen
脱酸化とは酸素が多すぎることを意味します
What happens when there is too much oxygen?
酸素が多すぎると何が起こるでしょうか？
algae will grow
藻が生えるだろう
so beautiful, green
とても美しい、緑
Look, this green algae
ほら、この緑藻
From this is NASA's aerial photo
こちらはNASAの航空写真です
You can see the way out of the sea
海から出る道が見えます
The sea estuary of the farming area, a piece of green
農業地帯の河口、緑のひとコマ
Very beautiful, green, green algae
とても美しい、緑、緑の藻
Chlorella can also be a healthy food
クロレラは健康食品にもなります
but it causes hypoxia
しかしそれは低酸素症を引き起こす
due to the proliferation of algae
藻類の繁殖により
its body sank
その体は沈みました
will consume the sheep along with the scorpion body
サソリの体ごと羊を食うだろう
resulting in the waters being completely devoid of sheep
その結果、水域には羊がまったくいなくなってしまう
A condition of hypoxia
低酸素状態
Oxygen-deficient to the point where fish and shrimp cannot grow
酸素が不足して魚やエビが成長できなくなる
this is the empty photo
これは空の写真です
Another piece of information about the aerial photo just now
先ほどの航空写真に関するもう一つの情報
you can see
見ることができます
The whole side is hypoxic
側面全体が低酸素状態です
The red ones are places that lack oxygen
赤いところは酸素が足りない場所です
Then it can cause the whole fish and shrimp to die
そうなると、魚やエビ全体が死んでしまう可能性があります
Instantly all die like this
このまま一瞬で全員死ぬ
How severely affected are the areas
地域はどれほど深刻な影響を受けていますか
look at this
これを見てください
this is me from
これは私です
Warsauce Institute
ワルソース研究所
as the information
情報として
look
見て
1850 to 1940
1850年から1940年
before the green revolution
緑の革命以前
This world is Binding
この世界は束縛されている
clean
綺麗
nothing
なし
good
良い
40 to 50 starts in the US
米国では40～50件のスタート
scorpion head
サソリの頭
may start to appear
現れ始めるかもしれない
Oxidation problem
酸化の問題
again
また
California also appeared
カリフォルニアも登場
Then the European side also began to appear
その後、ヨーロッパ側も現れ始めました
wow the problem is getting worse
うわ、問題はさらに悪化している
It's 1980
1980年です
It is worth mentioning that from 2000 to 2010
2000 年から 2010 年にかけてのことは言及する価値があります。
I think this issue is starting to be taken seriously
この問題は真剣に受け止められ始めていると思う
has slowed down slightly
わずかに減速しました
but still quite serious
でもまだかなり深刻
you see there are problems everywhere
どこにでも問題があることがわかります
In fact, the fertilizer problem on the mainland is also very serious.
実は本土の肥料問題も非常に深刻です。
We suffer from being in this place
私たちはこの場所にいることに苦しんでいます
Okay, so the layers of influence add up to be so broad.
そうですね、影響力の層は合計すると非常に広範囲になります。
So what is the only way to solve this problem?
では、この問題を解決する唯一の方法は何でしょうか?
Only by how can we increase the utilization efficiency of plant eggs
植物卵の利用効率を高めるにはどうすればよいか
Let it only use 30% of the 30% it just cast
キャストしたばかりの 30% のうち 30% のみを使用するようにします
It can be increased to 50%, 60% or even 70%, preferably 100%
50%、60%、さらには 70%、できれば 100% まで増やすことができます。
There will be no such excess flow out
そのような余分な流出はありません
So our experiment is
したがって、私たちの実験は
is to understand things like this from a plant point of view
このようなことを植物の観点から理解することです
Alright, let's talk about how plants use eggs
さて、植物が卵をどのように利用するかについて話しましょう
Most plants have three sources of eggs
ほとんどの植物には 3 つの卵源がある
The first is the leguminous
まずはマメ科です
just said
今言いました
It only has legumes that can make eggs
卵を作ることができるのはマメ科植物だけです
Legumes don't fix eggs by themselves
マメ科植物は自ら卵を固定しない
It is to live in symbiosis with the solid egg
それはグダンと共生すること
Then you can fix the egg
その後、卵を修正できます
What's a solid egg? Just like Haber's law
固い卵とは何ですか? ハーバーの法則と同じです
This bacterium is so smart
この細菌はとても賢い
before the invention of haber
ハーバーが発明される前
He knows how to put N2 in the air
彼はN2を空中に飛ばす方法を知っている
fix down
修正する
then fix down
それから固定します
So this is a leguminous plant
ということで、これはマメ科の植物です
but it produces root flow
しかし、それは根の流れを生み出します
That root flow is actually
その根幹の流れは実は
You can see this root flow
このルートの流れがわかります
It's actually a bit pink and red when it's made.
実際に作った時は少しピンクと赤がかっています。
Why is that red?
あれはなぜ赤いのですか？
This redness is the same as the redness of our blood vessels
この赤みは血管の赤みと同じです
It is a skin membrane Chinese medicine disease
皮膚膜の漢方疾患です
called like hemoglobin
ヘモグロビンと同じように呼ばれます
The snowball protein of this red snowball is the same
この赤い雪玉の雪玉タンパク質は同じです
Why does it have this protein to grab oxygen
なぜこのタンパク質が酸素を取り込むのですか
Because it fixes the N2 enzyme in the air
空気中のN2酵素を固定するため
Low function when aerobic
有酸素運動時の機能低下
So their symbiosis is very subtle
したがって、彼らの共生は非常に微妙です
what about it
それはどうですか
The food helps this egg-fixing fungus create an oxygen-deficient environment
この食物は、この定着菌が酸素欠乏環境を作り出すのに役立ちます。
The first way is to protect it
最初の方法はそれを保護することです
Enclosed to prevent oxygen from entering
酸素の侵入を防ぐために密閉されています
Then it produces this protein
そしてこのタンパク質を生成します
grab the oxygen
酸素を取り込む
With the help of these two
この二人の協力を得て
The egg-fixing efficiency of egg-fixing bacteria is very high
定着菌の定着効率は非常に高い
and so the two of them are great mates
そして彼ら二人は素晴らしい仲間です
He fixes his eggs and gives them to the plants
彼は卵を固定して植物に与えます
What do plants give back?
植物は何を返してくれるのでしょうか？
The sugar eggs produced by photosynthesis give it
光合成によって産生される卵から糖分が得られます。
So two symbiotic
つまり 2 つの共生
So botanists also have
したがって、植物学者も
Another dream is
もう一つの夢は
If all the plants in the world
もし世界中のすべての植物が
We can live together with Gu Danjun
ク・ダンジュンと一緒に暮らせます
Oh, let's save trouble
ああ、トラブルは避けられますよ
We don't have any of the so-called sorrows just now
いわゆる悲しみなんて今は無いよ
But this dream is still a little far away
でもこの夢はまだ少し遠い
because they know
彼らは知っているから
Between Gu Danjun and Plants
ク・ダンジュンと植物の間
There are several levels of interaction
インタラクションにはいくつかのレベルがあります
it's like falling in love
まるで恋に落ちたようだ
It takes a long time to talk to be able to succeed like this
このように成功するには話すのに長い時間がかかる
Then they have a lot of contacts
それから彼らはたくさんの連絡先を持っています
To be able to form such a special organ
このような特殊な器官を形成できるとは
then be careless
それから不注意になってください
so far
これまでのところ
Or is it limited to Douke plants that can do one thing?
それとも一つのことができるのはドゥーク植物に限られているのでしょうか？
What are the egg balls of other plants?
他の植物の卵球は何ですか?
mainly two
主に二つ
Nitrate, nitrate or saddle salt
硝酸塩、硝酸塩または鞍塩
talk about it here
ここでそれについて話してください
whole egg
全卵
in the earth
地球の中で
the looping situation
ループする状況
that just mentioned
それは今言った
fix the N2 in the air
空中にN2を固定する
there are several ways
いくつかの方法があります
an industrial method
工業的な方法
Or in fact nitrogen-fixing bacteria
あるいは窒素固定細菌
There are also some free-living nitrogen-fixing bacteria that can also do
また、自由生活性の窒素固定細菌もいくつかあります。
or just said
またはちょうど言った
Nitrogen-fixing bacteria that live in symbiosis with plants can do this
植物と共生する窒素固定細菌がそれを可能にします
In fact, most of our plants
実際、私たちの植物のほとんどは、
really usable
本当に使える
It's that legume that does this
これを行うのはそのマメ科植物です
most plants
ほとんどの植物
There are only two forms that can really be used
実際に使用できる形式は 2 つだけです
Aminitis or antiaciditis to use
アミノ炎または抗酸炎を使用する
That's actually
それは実際に
Most of the wet manure
湿った肥料のほとんどは
You don't have to take antiacid all
全ての制酸薬を摂取する必要はない
However, many currently commonly used urea
しかし、現在一般的に使用されている尿素の多くは、
superior
優越
But no matter what egg you give it
でも、どんな卵を与えても
within a day or two
1日か2日以内に
some bacteria in the soil
土壌中のいくつかの細菌
will quickly turn it into antiaciditis
すぐに抗酸炎に変わります
that's why
それが理由です
Another reason why the absorption efficiency of light fertilizer is so poor
軽質肥料の吸収効率が悪いもう一つの理由
Siolate is negatively charged
シオレートはマイナスに帯電しています
Soil ions and particles are also negatively charged
土壌イオンや粒子もマイナスに帯電しています
So shaved salt is actually very difficult to preserve in the soil.
そのため、削った塩を土壌に保存するのは実際には非常に困難です。
I just said that soon I don't want to convert to
すぐに変換したくないと言っただけです
When the plants have no time to absorb
植物が吸収する時間がないとき
Then it rained again and it was over
その後、また雨が降って、終わってしまいました
Xiaoyan is washed away and disappears
シャオヤンは流されて消えた
So a small part of the plants can also use amine inflammation
したがって、植物のごく一部はアミン炎症を利用することもできます。
However, the content of amine inflammation in the soil is relatively low
しかし、土壌中のアミン炎症の含有量は比較的低いです。
Soon it will be converted to sulphate
すぐに硫酸塩に変化します
So for plants
だから植物にとっては
Most of it is inhaled in the form of sulphate
そのほとんどは硫酸塩の形で吸入される
Our laboratory has been
私たちの研究室はこれまで、
It's about understanding how plants use siolate
植物がどのようにシオレートを利用するかを理解することです
Looking forward to the day we can think of a
を考えられる日を楽しみにしています
There can be good ways to increase the water use efficiency of plants
植物の水利用効率を高める良い方法があるかもしれない
what material do we use
どのような素材を使用していますか
not this one
これじゃない
This one was when I went to Canada with my students for a meeting
これは学生たちと会議のためにカナダに行ったときのものです
saw a tree
木を見た
Look, this is that Reu that is big
ほら、これが大きいレウだよ
The big tree on the west coast of Canada and California
カナダとカリフォルニアの西海岸にある大きな木
You can see how big this tree is
この木がいかに大きいかがわかります
But it looks like the Arab world
でもアラブ世界っぽいですね
Arab world is small
アラブ世界は狭い
how small is it
どのくらい小さいですか
Okay, you can put a copper plate in here
よし、ここに銅板を入れてもいいよ
you probably can't see
おそらく見えないでしょう
can't find a spot on this ground
この地面に場所が見つからない
The Arab world is actually about the size of a copper plate
アラブ世界は実際には銅板ほどの大きさです
that or you have seen that
それか、あなたはそれを見ました
The small tube that is often used in our laboratory
当研究室でよく使われている細管
its size like this
サイズはこんな感じ
So the Arab world is very inconspicuous, very small
つまりアラブ世界は非常に目立たず、非常に小さいのです
But it's a plant that we use as a model
でもそれは私たちがモデルとして使っている植物です
that is because it is small
それは小さいからです
what's the benefit of being small
小さいことのメリットは何ですか
Small is that the vice president doesn't need to give me a field
副大統領が私にフィールドを与える必要がないということは小さいことだ
i can experiment
実験できます
All the people who make plants experiment with rice or bath mud
植物を作る人は皆、お米やお風呂の泥を使って実験します
I think the vice president's head will be big like this
副社長の頭もこれくらい大きくなりそうだな
we use this
私たちはこれを使います
I just want a small room
小さな部屋が欲しいだけです
i can feed us all the time
いつでも私たちに食事を与えることができます
required plants
必要な植物
But it has all the information of all the plants in it
しかし、そこにはすべての植物のすべての情報が含まれています
so why we chose it as a model plant
なぜそれをモデル工場として選んだのか
You see, this is the one we use in our lab
ほら、これは私たちの研究室で使っているものです
15 cm patch dish
15cmパッチディッシュ
It is possible to plant 1000 small sprouts
小さな新芽を1000本植えることが可能
If you want to be in the newly sprouted
芽生えたばかりの中にいたいなら
When you are sifting bean sprouts
もやしをふるっているとき
you can be like this
あなたはこんな風になれるよ
So many provinces and cities can do things in such a small space
非常に多くの州や都市がこれほど小さなスペースで物事を行うことができます
So this is one of the advantages of Awakai
これが阿波会の利点の一つです
What is another advantage
もう一つの利点は何ですか
it has a short growing season
成長期が短い
from seed to seed
種から種へ
6 weeks to 8 weeks
6週間から8週間
it's amazing
すごい
In fact, I often follow
実は私もよくフォローしてます
Let me talk about it now, my Pitch D, when I was in my Ph.D.
ここで、私が博士課程にいたときのピッチ D について話しましょう。
A cycle of summer mother fungus is three days
夏母菌の周期は3日
That's me from the sheep to do the experiment for three days
3日間実験をする羊の私です
Then later switch to this experiment
その後、この実験に切り替えます
I can't wait
待ってられない
For six weeks I was watering all day
6週間の間、私は一日中水やりをしていました
Seedling growth is probably like me
苗の成長はきっと私に似ている
I hope he grows up soon
彼が早く成長することを願っています
I can do an experiment soon
もうすぐ実験できるよ
But it's too short for a professional
でもプロには短すぎる
six weeks
6週間
Six to eight weeks from seed to seed
種まきから種まきまで6～8週間
So that's why everyone didn't use big jobs later
だからみんな後で大きな仕事を使わなかったんだ
I took this small job
私はこの小さな仕事を引き受けました
This one is very convenient
これはとても便利です
We saw it and said wow this is the Arab world
私たちはそれを見て、「これがアラブ世界だ」と言いました。
But it's fun to be so big
でも大きくなると楽しいよ
Okay, so the first thing we need to know is
さて、それでは最初に知っておく必要があるのは、
The first job to use it is
それを使う最初の仕事は
How to suck it in from the picture
写真から吸い込む方法
Okay, between talking about how it sucks in
さて、それがどのように吸い込まれているかについて話すのはやめてください
Let me talk about the cell membrane first
まずは細胞膜についてお話しましょう
Every cell expresses its special cold mist
すべての細胞が特別な冷たい霧を表現します
content of something
何かの内容
But this cell and another cell
しかし、この細胞と別の細胞
why is it different
なぜ違うのですか
it needs a membrane to wrap it up
それを包む膜が必要だ
what is this membrane
この膜は何ですか
I think membrane is a super material
メンブレンはスーパーマテリアルだと思う
it this film
それはこの映画
inside a drop of oil on the water
水の上の一滴の油の中に
will it mix
混ざりますか
float on top
上に浮かぶ
That is, oil and water will not mix and separate.
つまり、油と水は混ざらず分離しません。
This membrane is oil
この膜は油です
Imagine that outside the cell is
細胞の外にあるものを想像してください。
thin layer of oil
薄い油の層
separate it
分けて
This oil is a super material
このオイルはスーパーマテリアルです
why
なぜ
first it separates it
まずそれを分離します
Then there is another advantage
それからもう一つメリットがあります
This membrane has a characteristic
この膜には特徴があります
it because here is acute
ここは急性だから
Intermediate is non-acute
中型は非急性
it does not allow holes
穴は許されない
you go to the membrane of the cell
あなたは細胞膜に行きます
rub a hole
穴をこする
as long as not too fast
速すぎない限り
you shrink back
あなたは縮こまってしまう
it will be back in no time
すぐに戻ってきます
super material
スーパーマテリアル
If our synthesized material is so good
私たちの合成した材料がとても良いなら
to do our stuff
私たちの仕事をするために
all great
都棒
never a hole
決して穴がない
Okay, but this cell can't be too nerdy
わかった、でもこの細胞はオタクになりすぎてはいけません
It wants to exchange its material with the outside world
自分の素材を外の世界と交換したい
it's going to stretch it needs something to come in
伸びるだろう、何かが入ってくる必要がある
And it needs to know what the outside environment is like
そして、外部環境がどのようなものであるかを知る必要があります
It's easy to react, what should I do?
反応しやすいのですがどうすればいいですか？
We will make holes in this membrane
この膜に穴を開けます
This is the protein on the membrane
これは膜上のタンパク質です
Then there are some proteins that do material exchange
次に、物質交換を行うタンパク質がいくつかあります
Some proteins are to understand changes in the external environment
一部のタンパク質は外部環境の変化を理解する
What our laboratory is doing is a hardening that is responsible for absorbing nitrates
私たちの研究室が行っているのは、硝酸塩の吸収を担う硬化です。
We're called transsclerostin, blood, blood, blood, blood
私たちはトランススクレロスチン、血液、血液、血液、血液と呼ばれています
Then I bought this structure in 1990 when I was a postdoctoral fellow at Grandpa Shen
その後、私がシェンおじいちゃんの博士研究員だった 1990 年にこの構造物を購入しました。
I started playing with this protein
このプロテインで遊び始めました
I didn't see what protein looks like until earlier this year
今年の初めまでプロテインがどのようなものかを知りませんでした
This structure was solved
この構造は解決されました
Never knew each other for 20 years
20年間お互いを知りませんでした
I don't know what he looks like
彼がどんな顔をしているのか分かりません
Today I finally saw his face like a mountain
今日やっと彼の山のような顔が見えた
he looks like this
彼はこんな感じです
So he is spread on this mold
だから彼はこの型の上に広がっている
remove the acid circle from outside the cell
細胞外からXiao酸サークルを抽出
a protein delivered into the cell
細胞に送達されるタンパク質
he is showing in the root
彼は根元に現れています
this is the root of a plant
これは植物の根です
root
根的
this is the apex
これが頂点です
root tip is fun
根元が楽しい
The root tip will secrete some Lunhua fluid
根の先端からは春華液が分泌されます。
So the root actually has another benefit
つまり、ルートには実際には別の利点があります
He wants to brick in the soil
彼は土にレンガを入れたいと思っています
so he wants that brick
それで彼はそのレンガが欲しいのです
his cells responsible for absorbing
吸収を担当する彼の細胞
These cells right in the epidermis
これらの細胞は表皮にあります
cells or even elongated
細胞、あるいは細長いもの
root hair
根毛
in charge of absorbing
吸収を担当する
The transporter we just talked about
先ほど話したトランスポーター
in these cells
これらの細胞の中で
responsible for putting outside
外に出す責任がある
Xiao sour circles in the soil
土壌中のシャオサワーサークル
suck into the plant
植物に吸い込む
there is a question
質問があります
just mentioned hydrochloric acid
先ほど塩酸について触れました
No matter what it looks like, the egg is in the soil
どう見えても卵は土の中にあります
or animal carcasses
または動物の死骸
Temperament also corrupts it
気質もそれを腐敗させる
convert to digestate
消化物に変換する
let plants absorb
植物に吸収させてください
But if the plant does not absorb
しかし、植物が吸収しない場合は、
or how
あるいはどうやって
salt in the soil
土壌中の塩分
less likely to be preserved
保存される可能性は低い
So the content of hydrochloric acid in the soil
つまり、土壌中の塩酸の含有量は
dramatic change
劇的な変化
this is what i borrow
これは私が借りているものです
This Tony Miller actually
実はこのトニー・ミラー
That's when I went to Lawson's Day
ローソンデーに行ったときのこと
Historic experimental place
歴史的な実験場
the visiting scholar
客員学者
Then he tested
それから彼はテストした
Digestive acid content in different places
さまざまな場所の消化酸含有量
10 meters measured once
10メートルを1回測定
wow you can see
うわー、わかりますか
it changes quickly
それはすぐに変わります
very big
とても大きい
big change
大きな変化
The difference in concentration can be as much as 10,000 times
濃度の差は10,000倍にもなる
then what to do
じゃあどうするか
Plants face such a changing environment
植物はこのような環境の変化に直面しています
how does it cope
どのように対処しますか
So plants have two absorption systems
つまり植物には2つの吸収システムがある
an absorption system called high compatibility
高適合性という吸収システム
One is a low clearance absorption system
1 つは低クリアランス吸収システムです
Well, you can see that it's increasing in concentration and it's getting higher
そうですね、集中力が増し、高くなっているのがわかります
When it is high, it is saturated, and it will no longer increase
高いと飽和してそれ以上増えなくなる
Later the second system started again
その後、2番目のシステムが再び開始されました
raised when the taller
背が高くなると高くなります
So what is the function of this high-low compatibility?
では、この高低互換性はどのような役割を果たしているのでしょうか?
low clearance you can see
クリアランスが低いことがわかります
When the concentration outside is high
屋外の集中力が高いとき
It can absorb a large amount of digestate
大量の塩酸を吸い込む可能性がある
and save it quickly
そしてすぐに保存してください
Can be used again in the future
将来的に再度使用することができます
So what is high compatibility?
では、高い互換性とは何でしょうか？
Just after the rain washes away
雨が洗い流した直後
Soil's depleting salt flow is running out
土壌から減少する塩分の流れがなくなりつつある
The plant still uses the system
工場では今でもそのシステムが使われている
I tried my best to find a way to get rid of the last drop of salt
最後の一滴の塩を取り除く方法を見つけるために最善を尽くしました
inhale again
もう一度吸う
This is the difference between the two systems
これが 2 つのシステムの違いです
A high-compatibility, a low-compatibility action system
互換性は高く、互換性は低いアクションシステム
That
それか
Plants also happen to have a lot of protein responsible for absorbing
植物には吸収に関与するタンパク質もたまたま豊富に含まれています
There is a group of proteins called NRT2
NRT2と呼ばれるタンパク質のグループがあります
The mouth jar we just mentioned belongs to this
先ほどの口壺はこれに属します
For a long time we thought it was low light and sexual
長い間、私たちはそれが低照度で性的なものだと考えていました
Then one day a master student
そしてある日修士課程の学生になるまで
In fact, he was still a college student at that time.
実際、彼は当時まだ大学生でした。
he found out about it
彼は見つけた
It is actually a very special protein
実はとても特殊なたんぱく質なのです
it is a double light and sex
それは二重の光とセックスです
That is to say, it has two functions
つまり2つの役割を持っています
It can also do high light and sexual absorption
高い光と性的吸収も行うことができます
Can also do low light and sex absorbing
低光量やセックス吸収も可能
So far probably only this protein
今のところおそらくこのプロテインだけ
have such characteristics
そのような特徴を持っています
It uses spiritual acidification to switch between high and low
精神的な酸性化を利用して高低を切り替えます。
when what is spiritual acidification
精神的な酸性化とは何ですか
Protein is often added with a spiritual acid
タンパク質には霊的な酸が添加されることがよくあります
When the protein is added with a spiritual acid
タンパク質にスピリチュアルな酸を加えると
it becomes recharge
それは充電になります
the whole structure will change
全体の構造が変わります
So it relies on protein acidification
つまりタンパク質の酸性化に依存しているのです
Turn it into a high light and sex transporter
ハイライトとセックストランスポーターに変えてください
When there is no spiritual acidification
精神的な酸性化がないとき
It is a low light and sensitive transporter
低照度で敏感なトランスポーターです
this is where we are
ここが私たちのいる場所です
Do a functional test of it to see something like this
機能テストを実行すると、次のような結果が得られます。
ok so how does it absorb next
さて、次はどうやって吸収するのでしょうか
today's little question
今日のちょっとした質問
I just want to say how about the plants
植物はどうですかと言いたいだけです
Calculation of minor salts in soil
土壌中の微量塩の計算
That animal is not the same as a plant
その動物は植物と同じではありません
animal in danger
危険にさらされている動物
what's the first reaction
最初の反応は何ですか
run
走る
Survive the fastest
最速で生き残れ
The genetic selection of that evolution
その進化の遺伝子選択
Probably run the fastest and keep it
おそらく一番速く走ってそれを維持する
what about the plants
植物はどうですか
Plants can't escape
植物は逃げられない
So I say plants are the bravest
だから私は植物が最も勇敢だと言います
people who face problems
問題に直面している人々
it never escapes its problems
それは決して問題から逃れられない
it has only one choice
選択肢は 1 つだけです
face it, deal with it
それに直面して、対処してください
Where does the oilseed vegetable stone fall and where does it grow
油糧種子植物石はどこに落ち、どこで成長するのか
How to make use of its existing environment
既存の環境をどう活用するか
do your best exercise
頑張って運動してください
this is the plant
これがその植物です
So he must have the highest courage
だから彼は最高の勇気を持っているに違いない
also have wisdom
知恵もある
what kind of wisdom
どのような知恵ですか
He must be very sensitive to detect
彼は非常に敏感に察知できるに違いない
changes in his external environment
彼の外部環境の変化
One of them is sulfonate
そのうちの1つはスルホン酸塩です
The amount of salt
塩の量
he wants to know
彼は知りたいと思っています
he can prepare
彼は準備ができます
This is plant sulphate sucked in
これは植物の硫酸塩を吸い込んだものです
How to use a picture
写真の使い方
good
良い
The cells of this plant are
この植物の細胞は、
There is a cell membrane just mentioned
先ほど述べた細胞膜があります
Cell membranes can absorb siolate
細胞膜はシオレートを吸収することができます
suck in
吸い込む
After Xiao Yan was inhaled
シャオヤンが吸入された後
Shallite will be reduced by a Shallate Coal
シャライトはシャレート石炭によって還元されます
converted to nitrite
亜硝酸塩に変換される
Where is Ya Xiao Salt?
ヤシャオ塩はどこにありますか？
Then send it to the karmic body of the plant
次にそれを植物のカルマ本体に送ります
Coal reduction through nitrite
亜硝酸塩による石炭削減
convert to acetate
アセテートに変換する
and then send
そして送信します
incobarate and then synthesize
インコバレートしてから合成する
manufacture amino acids
アミノ酸を製造する
Then we can grow
そうすれば私たちは成長できる
So actually
それで実際には
I just said that half of the human body
人間の体の半分ってさっき言ったけど
Eggs are from Harvard
卵はハーバード大学から
In fact, the half is synthesized by this method
実際、半分はこの方法で合成されています
Because we humans cannot absorb small salts
私たち人間は小さな塩分を吸収できないので、
with salt
塩で
We can only absorb organic eggs
私たちが吸収できるのは有機卵だけです
organic egg worker
有機卵労働者
who can transform the inorganic into organic
無機物を有機物に変えることができる人
just plants
ただの植物
so your plant
それであなたの植物は
those egg workers
あの卵労働者たち
Actually 100%
実は100％
almost one hundred percent
ほぼ100パーセント
not here directly or indirectly
直接的にも間接的にもここではない
the meat you eat
あなたが食べる肉
it also eats plants
植物も食べます
end up eating plants
結局植物を食べてしまう
so rely on this method
したがって、この方法に頼ってください
to convert inorganic into organic
無機物を有機物に変える
in order to supply the growth of the whole animal
動物全体の成長を助けるために
animal egg worker needs
動物の卵の労働者が必要とするもの
Okay, what about the plants?
さて、植物はどうですか？
Just mentioned, you see it can actually use hydrochloric acid
先ほども触れましたが、実際に塩酸を使用することができます。
You can also use saddle salt directly
サドルソルトを直接使用することもできます
It is actually more convenient to use saddle salt directly
実際にはサドルソルトを直接使用する方が便利です
You see it is missing two
2 つ足りないことがわかります
But saddle salt is actually very stressful and toxic to plants.
しかし、鞍塩は実際には植物にとって非常にストレスがかかり、有毒です。
Because of acid reduction... that saddle salt is in...
酸の還元のため…サドルソルトが入っている…
There is no way to store it in plants for a long time
植物内で長期間保存する方法はありません
So as soon as the plant sees the saddle salt
したがって、植物が鞍の塩を見つけるとすぐに、
got freaked out because it's going to metabolize it right away.
すぐに代謝されてしまうのでびっくりしました。
then metabolizing it costs energy
それを代謝するにはエネルギーがかかります
What about the hydrochloric acid?
塩酸はどうでしょうか？
it... the good thing about it is that it can store
それは...それの良いところは、それが保管できることです
it can store it inside the vacuole
液胞内に蓄えることができる
But it takes two more abilities to digest the salt...
しかし、塩を消化するにはさらに 2 つの能力が必要です...
energy to metabolize it
それを代謝するためのエネルギー
So plants don't want to...
だから植物はそれを望んでいません...
When you are free, prepare these enzymes first
時間が空いたら、まずこれらの酵素を準備してください
It needs to see, eh, is there really any disinfectant outside?
それは、えー、本当に外に消毒剤があるのか​​を確認する必要があります。
I just went... I just picked it up
行ってきたところです...拾ってきたところです
And just like that... like that...
そしてそのまま...そのように...
You have to do the math to see how much it was before this month
今月以前はいくらだったのか計算する必要があります
Just decided whether to eat steak or eat today...
ステーキを食べるか今日食べるかを決めたところです...
Eat that Yangchun noodles like this
陽春麺をこうやって食べる
So he has to see the changes outside to know
だから彼は外の変化を見て知る必要がある
So plants do
植物もそうなのです
Salt is not only a nutrient
塩分は単なる栄養素ではない
Still a fast-moving mob
まだまだ動きの遅いメンバーです
He wants to know that plants can know
彼は植物が知ることができることを知りたいと思っています
How much salt content
塩分含有量はどのくらいか
to change its own growth
自らの成長を変える
For example, if there is plenty in the early stage
たとえば、初期段階でたくさんある場合
It can grow it better like this
このままだともっと良く成長できるよ
so grow
だから成長する
planted dormancy
植えられた休眠
air hole switch
エアホールスイッチ
growth of leaves
葉の成長
even what i just said
私が今言ったことでも
just metabolized
代謝されたばかりの
The genes involved in the metabolism of salt
塩の代謝に関わる遺伝子
gene expression
遺伝子発現
are regulated by sulphate
硫酸塩によって規制されている
That's actually
それは実際に
this reaction
この反応
what we call the primary response
私たちが一次反応と呼ぶもの
Primary Nitrous Bounce
一次亜窒素バウンス
This is a response to the expression of a gene
これは遺伝子の発現に対する反応です
For example, those genes just now
例えば今の遺伝子は
or the genes responsible for the uptake here
またはここでの取り込みに関与する遺伝子
We get as an example
例として挙げます
It's when you have amine inflammation
アミン炎症が起こっているときです
very low performance
非常に低いパフォーマンス
When giving it antiaciditis
抗酸炎を与える場合
The performance reached the top in 30 minutes and then fell
パフォーマンスは 30 分で頂点に達し、その後低下しました
quick response
迅速な対応
So we call it touch response
したがって、それをタッチ応答と呼びます
very fast
とても早い
We've known this reaction since 1989
私たちはこの反応を 1989 年から知っていました
It's like saying 20 years ago
20年前に言ってるようなもんだ
Know it 25 years ago
25年前に知ってた
have this reaction
この反応がある
know the reaction
反応を知る
everyone is thinking
みんなが考えている
Plants Known to Support Undo Aciditis
胃酸炎をサポートすることが知られている植物
how to detect
検出方法
Who is in charge of detecting
誰が検出を担当するのか
this is what we are all looking for
これが私たち全員が探しているものです
we are also looking for
私たちも探しています
So I use this poem to
そこで私はこの詩を使って、
tell us how to find it
見つけ方を教えてください
It is re-li Xunla ten thousand degrees
リリー・シュンラ万度です
look back
振り返って
That man is at the burning mountain
あの男は燃える山にいる
we didn't expect
私たちは期待していませんでした
early morning
早朝
It turned out to be our laboratory
それは私たちの研究室であることが判明しました
I've been doing this protein
私はこのプロテインをやっています
Just to know how charcoal cures external acid inflammation
木炭が外部の酸性炎症をどのように治すかを知りたい
how much protein
タンパク質の量
So it is not only a
したがって、それは単なるものではありません
Transport protein transports hydrochloric acid from the outside of the cell to the inside of the cell
輸送タンパク質は塩酸を細胞の外側から細胞の内側に輸送します。
it's also a sensor
それもセンサーです
Sensing external acid salts
外部の酸塩の感知
At this time, there is no need to put the cells
このとき、セルを入れる必要はありません。
Just a little bit of it can regenerate gene expression
ほんの少しの量で遺伝子発現を再生することができます
I just said that he is a heavy female patroller.
さっき言ったけど、彼は重装の女性パトロール隊員だ。
look back
振り返って
That man is at the burning mountain
あの男は燃える山にいる
Looking back on this smoke
この煙を振り返ると
It sounds like only looking back
振り返っているだけのように聞こえる
In fact, this process is ups and downs
実際、このプロセスには浮き沈みがあります
How to find this gene
この遺伝子を見つける方法
how to let us know
どのように私たちに知らせるか
indeed he
確かに彼は
that's actually
それは実際に
the story goes so
話はそうなります
we were thinking then
私たちはそのとき考えていました
we all know this reaction
私たちは皆この反応を知っています
Participating molecules
関与する分子
we are all looking
私たちは皆探しています
don't know who
誰だか分からない
then we will
それなら私たちはそうします
found a protein gene
タンパク質遺伝子を発見した
Protein gene is what I just said
タンパク質遺伝子とは今言った通りです
he will add protein
彼はプロテインを追加します
An enzyme of lingonic acid root
凌酸根的一個酵素
One of the genes CIPK8 we found
私たちが発見した遺伝子の1つCIPK8
At that time I wanted to say
あの時言いたかったのは
is he involved in this
彼はこれに関わっていますか
Primary reaction of antiaciditis
抗酸炎の一次反応
found out that he was indeed involved
彼が実際に関与していたことを知った
for normal plants
通常の植物の場合
When he gave 25 minimolar of antiacid inflammation
彼が25ミニモルの抗酸炎症薬を投与したとき
His performance can be like this
彼のパフォーマンスはこんな感じかも
But when the CIPK8
しかし、CIPK8 のとき
lower
低い
then we thought
それから私たちは考えました
Wow, great
うわー、すごい
We find the first gene involved in this process
このプロセスに関与する最初の遺伝子を発見
Then we feel good about ourselves
そうすれば、私たちは自分自身に満足できるようになります
The paper will be sent to PNS
論文はPNSに送信されます
Then the paper is sent to CIPK8S
その後、用紙は CIPK8S に送信されます。
I also breathed a sigh of relief
私も安堵のため息をつきました
Hurry up and take the kids to Hualien for vacation
急いで子供たちを花蓮に連れて休暇に行きましょう
Then I go to the ideal land to go on vacation
それから私は休暇を過ごすために理想的な土地に行きます
Then the door to my room opened
その時、私の部屋のドアが開きました
the phone rang
電話が鳴りました
paper was rejected
紙は拒否されました
Our kind of paper is often rejected
私たちの種類の論文は拒否されることが多い
And having a dream is actually a way to do research.
そして、夢を持つということは、実は研究をするための手段なのです。
that's good
それは良い
Then my students were about to cry
すると生徒たちは泣きそうになった
Because he is waiting for a graduation
卒業を待っているので
Going to America to be a Poster
ポスターになるためにアメリカへ行く
His whole plan is fine
彼の計画全体はうまくいっている
just wait here
ここで待っててください
Hurry up how to accept this
急いでこれをどう受け止めるか
then i will say
それから私は言います
what did the other party say
相手は何と言ったか
He said the other party said
相手がこう言ったそうです
The difference is too small
差が小さすぎる
I think the difference is too small
その差は小さすぎると思う
our gold
私たちの金
Such a beautiful experiment proves that he has a difference
このような美しい実験は、彼には違いがあることを証明しています
But he said the difference is too small
しかし彼はその差は小さすぎると言いました
The difference is too small is this
差が小さすぎるんだよこれ
traits of this gene
この遺伝子の特徴
how can i change
どうすれば変えられますか
Ruined
台無しにされた
I just say
私はちょうど言います
At that time the child was in the room
その時子供は部屋にいました
I said I'll wait for half an hour
30分待つって言ったのに
wait for me for half an hour
30分待ってください
I'll call back
折り返し電話します
What am I doing for half an hour?
私は30分も何をしているのでしょうか？
Chase the little ones to the pool
小さな子供たちをプールに追いかけてください
you have been to the ideal land
あなたは理想の地に来ました
swimming pool outside the room
部屋の外にプール
So I sent the kids to the pool
それで子供たちをプールに行かせました
rush to the swimming pool
スイミングプールに急ぐ
I have time to think what to do
何をすべきか考える時間はある
only then did i think
そのとき初めて私は思いました
ask him to do an experiment
彼に実験をするよう頼む
This is the following experiment
これは次の実験です
we just test
私たちはただテストするだけです
i told him to do it
私は彼にそうするように言いました
call him in half an hour
30分以内に彼に電話する
I will ask him to test
彼にテストしてもらいます
highest performance
最高表現量
Then I found out that
それから私はそれを知りました
Wow
おお
WireTab is just like the absorption just now
WireTabは今の吸収と同じです
Also two Faces
フェイスも二つある
There are two modes of action, high and low
高モードと低モードの 2 つの動作モードがあります
Just CIPK8
CIPK8だけ
Only in the place of Lower Fini
下フィニの場所のみ
So this data
それでこのデータは
Let this student Paper
この生徒に論文を書かせます
send out to accept
受け入れるために送信する
Of course I dare not use 4PS
もちろん4PSはあえて使いません
Send it to another Jono at this time
この時点で別の Jono に送信します
accepted students graduated
合格した学生は卒業しました
but tell me
でも教えて
Wow
おお
This mouth must be involved
この口が関与しているに違いない
We must be involved with that transfer protein
私たちはその転移タンパク質に関与する必要があります
So this experiment
そこでこの実験は
In fact let me start to know that
実際、それを知り始めましょう
Extraoral involvement
口腔外の関与
So sometimes I see Paper
だから時々紙を見るんだ
being traveled is sometimes
旅行されることもあります
crisis is opportunity
危機はチャンスだ
not on that knot
その結び目ではなく
I probably have no way of convincing students to do this experiment
おそらく学生たちにこの実験をするよう説得する方法はないと思います
this experiment is really hard
この実験は本当に難しいです
Actually so far
実はここまで
There are not many people in our laboratory
私たちの研究室にはあまり人がいません
Really dare to challenge this experiment
本当にこの実験に挑戦してみませんか
then we find out
そうすればわかります
The mouth-wrist mutant's response hit rock bottom
口と手首のミュータントの反応はどん底に達した
This leads us to say that the mouth and wrist are likely involved
このことから、口と手首が関与している可能性が高いと言えます。
But we don't know that the evidence isn't enough
しかし、証拠が十分でないことはわかりません
Another breakthrough is that we found a
もう一つの画期的な発見は、
A mutant that isolates the function of uptake sensing
取り込み感知機能を分離する変異体
it can't absorb
それは吸収できない
But the message transmission is still normal
ただし、メッセージの送信は正常に行われています
This shows that it is directly involved in
これは、に直接関与していることを示しています。
With this evidence we can explain
この証拠があれば説明できる
This wrist is what we have been looking for for more than 20 years
この手首は私たちが20年以上探していたものです
Who the hell is sensing these soils
いったい誰がこの土壌を感知しているのか
Content of fermented salt
発酵塩の含有量
So I drew this picture
それでこの絵を描きました
Said the wrist is like a tongue
手首は舌のようなものだと言いました
Help plants know in the soil
植物が土壌のことを知るのを助ける
wow! is this delicious for dinner today
うわー、今日の夕食は美味しいですか？
how does it taste today
今日はどんな味ですか
then i will find one
それなら私が一つ見つけます
artist painted
アーティストが描いた
At that time, if the competition
そのとき、競争だったら、
Sale,Jono's cover
セール、ジョノのカバー
but you i failed
でもあなた、私は失敗しました
Sale has no vision
セールにはビジョンがない
That cover is really enough
あのカバーだけで本当に十分だよ
like a notebook cover
ノートカバーのように
air element
エアエレメント
there is another funny thing
もう一つ面白いことがあります
Once at an international conference
ある国際会議で
i will tell the story
私はその話をします
Then show this slide
次に、このスライドを見せてください
this slide
このスライド
then i said
それから私は言いました
This turns white like a tongue
これが舌のように白くなります
I'm probing... probing that brain
私は調べている...その脳を調べている
Then the next speaker is a
それでは、次の講演者は、
people from france
フランスから来た人たち
Then he also spoke on the same subject
それから彼も同じ話題について話しました
similar topics
似たような話題
But what did he draw?
しかし、彼は何を描いたのでしょうか？
draw a dog's nose
犬の鼻を描く
so he said
それで彼は言いました
Chinese people use their tongues
中国人は舌を使います
Come to discover the deliciousness of his food
彼の食べ物の美味しさを発見しに来てください
We French smell food with our noses
私たちフランス人は鼻で食べ物の匂いを嗅ぎます
Hehehe
ふふふ
good
良い
Then today one is to say
そこで今日、一つ言いたいのは、
How is food calculated?
食事はどのように計算されますか?
The content of antiacid in the soil
土壌中の抗酸含有量
well, plants count
まあ、植物は数えます
One, two, three outside
1、2、3 外側
One outside, two, three, ten
外側に 1 つ、2 つ、3 つ、10 つ
How does it know whether there is more or less outside?
外部に存在するものが多いか少ないかをどうやって知るのでしょうか?
just use the wrist
手首だけを使ってください
Because just said there are two kinds of oral and wrist
先ほど口と手首が2種類あると言ったので
The ability to grasp antiacid inflammation lightly and firmly
抗酸性炎症を軽く、しっかりと把握する能力
So when the concentration is low outside
したがって、屋外で集中力が低いときは、
it will be acidified
酸性化してしまいます
When the concentration outside is high
屋外の集中力が高いとき
it won't acidify
酸性化しないよ
So it counts by mouth and wrist
つまり口と手首で数えます
Is the concentration outside high or low?
外の濃度は高いのか低いのか？
When the outside concentration is low
外部濃度が低い場合
It will be Binding on a high-resolution position
高解像度の位置でのバインディングとなります
Just posted this Fossuration again
この Fossuration をもう一度投稿しました
When the mouth and wrist are acidified
口や手首が酸性になっている場合
It's a high-complexity transsclerostin
それは高度に複雑なトランススクレロスチンです
then this time
それから今度は
It also issued a relatively low amount of elite performance
また、エリートパフォーマンスの発行量も比較的少なかった
When the concentration outside is relatively low
屋外の濃度が比較的低い場合
When the output is very high, he is three good, he does not want to do anything
生産性が非常に高いとき、彼は 3 つの状態にあり、何もしたくありません。
ad hoc
このために
At this time, he is a low-light and sexual transporter
現時点では、彼は低光量の性的トランスポーターです
A transport protein that can be absorbed in large quantities
大量に吸収される輸送タンパク質
At this time, he can also express a high amount of genes
現時点では、大量の遺伝子を発現することもできます。
So the mouth and the wrist are really quality
口元も手首も本当に上質です
He is the porter who moved Xiao Chuanyuan in from the outside
彼はシャオ・チュアンユアンを外から引っ越しさせたポーターです
He's in the goalie, just said look outside
彼はゴールキーパーにいる、外を見ろと言ったところだ
Uncle look outside
おじさんは外を見て
He's also a messenger of messages.
彼はメッセージのメッセンジャーでもあります。
He also needs to flush this message into the nucleus
また、このメッセージを核にフラッシュする必要があります
to make genes behave like this
遺伝子にこのように振る舞わせるには
This is how the plant calculates the concentration change outside
これは、植物が屋外の濃度変化を計算する方法です。
Next, how do plants remember the concentration changes outside?
次に、植物は屋外の濃度変化をどのように記憶しているのでしょうか？
My use of memory is actually a bit anthropomorphic
私の記憶の使い方は実は少し擬人化的です
It really means that the plant is actually like this little white rabbit
それは、植物が実際にはこの小さな白いウサギに似ていることを意味します
where did this little white rabbit come from
この小さな白いウサギはどこから来たのですか
Ellie is the one in Sleepwalking
エリーは夢遊病の人です
Little rabbit, he is not too late to get one of these
小さなウサギさん、これを手に入れるのに遅すぎることはありません
He's been with him for a long time
彼は長い間一緒にいる
How does he calculate the time to change the time?
彼は時刻を変更する時間をどのように計算しているのでしょうか?
what is time change
時間変更とは何ですか
Actually it is like this
実際はこんな感じです
We just talked about the expression of those genes
先ほど、遺伝子の発現について話しました。
we saw shortly
私たちはすぐに見ました
His mark is to give him 25 minimum high concentration time
彼の評価は最低 25 時間の高い集中時間を与えることです
he raises
彼は上げます
But after reaching the peak he comes down
しかし、頂点に達した後、彼は降りる
Still low at 16 hours
16時間ではまだ低い
And what if you give him a low dose?
そして、低用量を彼に与えたらどうなるでしょうか？
Although the bid was not high when he just died
彼が亡くなったばかりのときは入札額は高くなかったが、
after a short down
短いダウンの後
he went up
彼は上がった
That is to say, the concentration in the short-term and long-term
つまり、短期集中と長期集中です。
would be totally different and the opposite reaction
全く違う、逆の反応になるだろう
why is it so complicated
なぜそんなに複雑なのか
Why long time vs short time concentration
長時間集中力と短時間集中力の理由
would have a completely different reaction
全く違う反応をするだろう
This actually works with
これは実際に動作します
A picture from this dragon plant physiology textbook to represent
このドラゴン植物生理学教科書からの写真を表現する
It was also mentioned just now
先ほども言われましたが
The higher the concentration the plants can grow
濃度が高いほど植物は成長できる
But after a concentration
でも集中した後は
Actually it won't increase much anymore
実はもうあまり増えない
Even when the concentration is too high
濃度が高すぎても
plant growth will decrease
植物の成長が減少します
So too much is actually not good for plants.
つまり、多すぎることは実際には植物にとって良くありません。
So the opposite reaction just now
それで今は逆の反応
It is an adjustment function
調整機能です
But when the concentration outside is high
でも、外の濃度が高いときは
It cannot be insatiable and still
飽くことなく静止することはできません
it can't take it
それは耐えられない
So it tries to turn it off
それでそれをオフにしようとします
when it's low outside
外が低いとき
It says I'm still starving
まだ飢えていると言う
not enough not enough
十分ではありません十分ではありません
But plants know how to say
しかし植物は言うことを知っています
how long has it been starving
どれくらい飢えていますか
How to do this kind of time change?
このような時間の変更はどのように行うのでしょうか？
We found that there is a
があることがわかりました。
I just talked about acidifying it
先ほど酸性化についてお話しました
The other is an effect of deleaching and acidifying it
もう一つは脱漂白・酸性化の効果です。
protein delynchase
タンパク質脱リン酵素
we named it
私たちはそれを名付けました
And he actually works differently in the short term than in the long term.
そして実際、彼は長期的な場合と短期的な場合ではやり方が異なります。
He was a good guy when he was short
背が低い時はいい奴だった
He can help this protein gene plum go pro-acidifying mouth tank
彼は、このタンパク質遺伝子プラムが口のタンクを酸性にするのを助けることができます
but for a long time
しかし長い間
He in turn does a complete opposite
彼は今度は全く逆のことをする
Removed the acid root
酸の根を取り除いた
So he short time and long time
だから彼は短い時間と長い時間を
playing two completely different roles
全く異なる2つの役割を演じる
Such a role reversal makes gene expression low for a short time
このような役割の逆転により、遺伝子発現が短期間低下します。
Long time is high performance
長時間でも高性能
The gene named him Anny
遺伝子は彼をアニーと名付けた
In fact, the name is very interesting
実は名前がとても面白いんです
I don't know if you watch Star Wars or not
スターウォーズを見ているかどうかは知りませんが、
Not a Skywalker in Star Wars
スターウォーズのスカイウォーカーではない
He was a chivalrous man
彼は騎士道的な男だった
Later, it was due to personality defects
あとは性格の欠陥が原因だった
Finally turned around and became a bad guy
ついに一転して悪者になってしまった
So I use him to mean Anny
だから私は彼をアニーという意味で使います
Anny is the name
アニーって名前です
this protein
このタンパク質
It does the exact opposite of what it does in the short run versus the long run
短期的な場合と長期的な場合ではまったく逆のことを行います。
Let the plants do the time change
植物に時間を変えてもらいましょう
This is to tell you how plants know
これは植物がどのように認識しているかを説明するためのものです
Concentration change, how to do time change
濃度変更、時間変更のやり方
Alright, next this is the hydrochloric acid out there
はい、次は塩酸です。
What about the hydrochloric acid in plants?
植物に含まれる塩酸はどうでしょうか？
How to know the digestate in plants?
植物の消化物を知るにはどうすればよいですか?
In fact, it needs to know whether there are many outside
実際、外部に多くのものが存在するかどうかを知る必要があります。
You also need to know if there is enough storage in it.
十分なストレージがあるかどうかも知る必要があります。
it can do the best conditioning
最高のコンディショニングが可能です
How do you know inside?
どうやって内部を知るのですか？
We found that there is a gene that is responsible for detecting
を検出する遺伝子があることが分かりました。
Well, this gene is called NRT1.13
さて、この遺伝子はNRT1.13と呼ばれています
Where does it manifest itself?
それはどこで現れますか？
Apex, we know that this plant is from the Arabian kingdom
アペックス、私たちはこの植物がアラビア王国のものであることを知っています
leaves grow under it
その下に葉が生える
When the leaves grow for a while and are old enough
葉がしばらく成長して十分な年齢になったとき
The Arab world will smoke this flower shaft
アラブ世界はこの花の軸を吸うだろう
What about after pulling this flower shaft?
花軸を描いた後はどうでしょうか？
this plant
この植物
This internode will grow a leaf
この節間から葉が生えてきます
Come here again and it will bloom
またここに来れば咲くでしょう
There is a flower stalk coming out
花茎が出てきました
So this section
したがって、このセクションは
In fact like one of its plants
実際、その植物の一つのように
checkpoint
チェックポイント
It needs to know how to redistribute nutrients
栄養素を再分配する方法を知る必要がある
Then the gene is expressed in this
すると、この中で遺伝子が発現します。
knot this place
この場所で結びます
what about this knot
この結び目はどうですか
And it just happens to grow out
そしてそれはたまたま成長するだけです
The place where the test capital will grow
テスト資金が成長する場所
The gene behaves like this
遺伝子は次のように動作します
What is this gene involved in?
この遺伝子は何に関与しているのでしょうか?
first it controls the net
まずネットをコントロールする
The amount of hydrochloric acid that moves sideways
横に移動する塩酸の量
Where is the expression of this gene?
この遺伝子はどこで発現しているのでしょうか?
Plants are delivered from wooden cloth
植物は木製の布からお届けします
so this plant
それでこの植物
Wooden cloth is this cell
木布がこのセルです
Later I will talk more about what is wood cloth
木布とは何か詳しくお話します
Actually a plant
実は植物って、
imagine a
一つを想像してみてください
dead water pipe from root to above ground
根元から地上までの死水管
After nutrients are absorbed from the roots
根から養分を吸収した後
transport from the xylem to the aboveground
木部から地上への輸送
The plant sent a guard to stand next to the xylem
植物は木部の隣に警備員を派遣した
check it out
見てみな
What is the content of silver pinate in the xylem
木部のピン酸銀の含有量は何ですか
This pawn is just this 1.13
このポーンはまさにこれ 1.13
standing right inside the cell next to the xylem
木部の隣の細胞内に立っています
green cells
緑色のセル
Let's look at how high the silver pinionate content is in the xylem
木部におけるピニオン酸銀の含有量がどのくらい高いかを見てみましょう
the first to regulate
最初に規制するのは
How far should I send it to the side?
どこまで横に送ればいいですか？
also regulates its flowering
開花も調節します
When it is broken, it is found that it blooms later than normal plants
折ってみると、通常の植物よりも遅く開花することがわかります
And this effect is not affected when the concentration outside is very high
そして、この効果は、屋外の濃度が非常に高い場合には影響を受けません。
Differences are only seen at low concentrations
違いは低濃度でのみ見られます
This gene is too low when measuring speed over there
あそこで速度を測るとこの遺伝子は低すぎる
Find a way to get the plants ready
植物を準備する方法を見つける
Come to the quilt master to get up to make it bloom again
キルトマスターのところに来て、再び花を咲かせるために立ち上がってください
Without this quilt master
このキルトマスターがなければ
I can't flower normally.
普通に花が咲きません。
It is even said that it will affect the growth of the measured capital
測定資本の成長に影響を与えるとも言われています
Or the trees that measure capital like this
あるいは、このように資本を測定する木
So actually a plant
それで実際には植物です
you plant two plants
あなたは2つの植物を植えます
Sometimes it looks different
違うように見えることもあります
Measurements actually affect the shape of its entire plant
測定値は実際に植物全体の形状に影響を与えます
There are many factors such as temperature and sunlight
気温や日照など様々な要因がありますが、
Nutrients also affect
栄養素も影響する
Xiao Suinyan is also a factor in controlling this French
シャオ・スイニャンもこのフランスをコントロールする要因となっている
This is how Xiao Suanyan sensed
シャオ・スアンヤンはこう感じた
I'm going to talk pretty fast
かなり早口で話します
But there's one more thing I'll talk about
でも、もう一つ話したいことがあります
It's how plants are sucked in Xiao Suinyan
シャオ・スイニャンに植物が吸い込まれる様子
how to deliver
配達方法
Make effective use of different parts
さまざまなパーツを有効活用する
ok , that we just talked about
わかりました、今話したばかりです
Except for a few that are sensing changes
変化を感じている少数を除いて
And some are actually shipping
実際に出荷しているものもある
After the plant wasting inflammation is inhaled
植物の消耗炎症を吸入した後
and deliver it efficiently
そしてそれを効率的に届ける
Take advantage of where you really need it
本当に必要な場所で活用する
Then our laboratory also knows that
それなら私たちの研究室もそれを知っています
the various steps involved
含まれるさまざまな手順
Today, I will focus on these three genes
今日はこの3つの遺伝子に焦点を当てます。
It's doing some redistribution of wasting inflammation inside the blade
刃の内側で無駄な炎症を再配分しています。
ok , before i talk about this i ' ll talk about it
わかりました、これについて話す前に話しましょう
Do you know how tall the tallest tree is?
一番高い木の高さはどれくらいか知っていますか？
100 meters high
高さ100メートル
This Ruiwu in California
カリフォルニアにあるこの瑞烏
about 115 meters high
高さ約115メートル
About how high is this building? About a third of it
この建物の高さはどれくらいですか? 3分の1くらいです
101 building height
101 建物の高さ
Did you think of a fun question
面白い質問を考えましたか
Our water will reach 30% of the building height
私たちの水は建物の高さの 30% に達します
how much horse power do we need to hit it up
それを達成するにはどのくらいの馬力が必要ですか
But plants don't need a little effort
でも植物には少しの努力も必要ありません
just send it up
ただ送ってください
How did the water rush so high?
どうやって水があんなに高くなったのでしょうか？
For True Dispersion
真の分散を目指して
Why does True Dispersion have this magical power?
なぜ True Dispersion にはこのような魔法の力があるのでしょうか?
Actually rely on this
実はこれを頼りにしている
The true dispersion effect is dispersed in water
本当の分散効果は水に分散すること
is a plant within an hour
1時間以内の植物です
Probably all the water needs to be changed once
おそらく一度すべて水を交換する必要があります。
The water in its whole body needs to be changed once
全身の水を一度入れ替える必要がある
It's a waste to think about it, right?
考えるのは無駄ですよね？
That's why agriculture needs so much water
だからこそ農業には大量の水が必要なのです
Then why does it have an advantage to use true dispersion
では、なぜ真の分散を使用することに利点があるのでしょうか。
It's actually sending us and you to fight under the sun
それは実際に私たちとあなたを太陽の下で戦わせることになります
Especially these days, you go to fight under the sun
特に最近は太陽の下で戦いに行く
20 minutes is a bit unbearable without an umbrella
20分は傘がないとちょっと耐えられない
Plant I told you it can't hide
植物、隠れることはできないって言ったよね
So it relies on this water to dissipate the heat
したがって、熱を放散するためにこの水に依存しています
Then why is the water pumped so high?
では、なぜ水はこれほど高く揚水されるのでしょうか？
The main thing is to say yes, after steaming this water and using it dry
重要なことは、この水を蒸して乾燥させた後、「はい」と答えることです
This is the cell, the cell inside the leaf
これは細胞です、葉の中の細胞です
We know that there is a thing in the plant cell called the leaf
私たちは植物の細胞の中に葉と呼ばれるものがあることを知っています
cell wall
細胞壁
So the cell wall has very, very thin pores
したがって、細胞壁には非常に薄い孔があります
Come to think of it, there's water in those holes
そういえばあの穴には水が入ってた
when the water disappears
水がなくなると
There is no water in this hole
この穴には水はありません
This creates a hollow when there is no water
水がないときに空洞ができる
water becomes a hollow
水が空洞になる
We just know water doesn't like cavities the last thing
私たちは、水が虫歯を最も嫌うということを知っていました。
it tries to make it up again
それは再びそれを取り戻そうとする
This power is the power it makes up for
この力はそれを補う力です
it wants to reduce it doesn't want to have a pit
減らしたい、穴は開けたくない
it's going to level it
それは平準化するだろう
The force of this leveling is just
このレベリングの力はまさに
Let it refer to the ability to draw water from the ground
地面から水を汲む能力を指します
Rush up to 30 stories
最大 30 話まで駆け上がる
let it go up
上げさせてください
This path is called wooden steps
この道は木段と呼ばれています
The wooden steps seem to be very similar
木の階段はこんな感じ
Plants are actually two highways
植物は実際には 2 つの高速道路です
a wooden step
木の段
just said
今言いました
Use truth and goodness to flush it
真実と善を使ってそれを洗い流してください
go take it
取りに行ってください
Its source of power is the effect of truth and goodness
その力の源は真実と善の効果である
Then the direction of common recitation is mainly from the root of the bottom all the way to the third step
その場合、一般的な暗唱の方向は主に下の根から3番目のステップまでです。
Then there is another way, the plug tube.
それから、プラグチューブという別の方法もあります。
Wooden step for cork
コルク用木製ステップ
It's a bit like our arteries and veins
それは私たちの動脈と静脈に似ています
but
しかし
The wooden step was just mentioned
木の階段については先ほど触れました
The plug tube is not the same as the wooden step
プラグチューブは木製ステップとは異なります
it is a living cell
それは生きた細胞です
but it is because
でもそれは
it's a hollowed out living cell
それは空洞になった生きた細胞です
So its transportation can also be faster
そのため輸送も速くなります
Normal cell delivery is too slow
通常の細胞送達が遅すぎる
it's a hollowed out living cell
それは空洞になった生きた細胞です
But since it is a living cell
でも生きた細胞なので
Its delivery is mainly due to the difference in osmotic pressure
その送達は主に浸透圧の違いによるものです
So it will always be the most osmotic
したがって、常に最も浸透性が高くなります
the most abundant place
最も豊かな場所
Send to places where material is relatively scarce
資材が比較的不足している場所に送る
And what is the most abundant place
そして、最も豊かな場所はどこですか
The inside of the plant is actually the place where photosynthesis is strongest
実は植物の内部は光合成が最も盛んな場所なのです
Because sugar is the largest substance in plants
砂糖は植物の中で最大の物質なので、
So it's basically from where the photosynthesis is strongest
基本的に光合成が最も強い場所からです
sent to weaker places
より弱い場所に送られる
This is the xylem and cork
これが木部とコルクです
that just said
それは今言ったばかりです
Those three genes are responsible for the redistribution of these ions
これら 3 つの遺伝子は、これらのイオンの再分布を担当します。
Among them, 1.11 and 1.12
その中で、1.11と1.12
It is responsible for saying the way to change the runway
滑走路を変更する方法を決定する責任がある
Transfers hydrochloric acid from mature large leaves to young leaves
成熟した大きな葉から若い葉に塩酸を移動させます。
good
良い
what about the gene
遺伝子はどうですか
Well, we just talked about the ones from the ground
さて、私たちは地面からのものについて話しました
it works by virtue
それは美徳によって機能します
Reaction
再作用
What is the stronger effect of true dispersion?
真の分散のより強力な効果は何ですか?
bigger leaves
大きな葉
True Sancao is the strongest
真の三曹は最強だ
OK , so a whole lot of sate
OK、それではたっぷりの塩です
will run to large mature leaves
大きく成熟した葉に向かって走ります
At this time, its salt content is very high
この時期は塩分濃度が非常に高いので、
The young leaves have very low sulphate content
若い葉には硫酸塩含有量が非常に低い
Young people want to grow up, what should we do?
若者は成長したいのですが、どうすればよいでしょうか？
It's...less salty
それは...塩気が少ないです
What should we do at this time?
この時、私たちは何をすべきでしょうか？
It relies on the two transformation proteins 1.11 and 1.12
2 つの遷移タンパク質 1.11 および 1.12 に依存します。
in the sieve
ふるいの中
Make these more in...
これらをさらに...
Salt conversion treasure road from xylem
木部からの塩転換宝道
into the sieve
ふるいに入れる
What is the result of this?
この結果はどうなるのでしょうか?
The amount of mature leaves sent in is reduced
送られる成熟した葉の量が減少します
But take these salts
でも、これらの塩を摂取してください
Used to supplement the deficiency of young leaves
若葉の不足を補うために使用されます。
So plants are smart
だから植物は賢いんだよ
it knows
それは知っています
Hey, don't eat so much
ねえ、そんなに食べないでください
give young people something like this
若い人たちにこのようなものを与えてください
What is the effect of such a mechanism of action?
このような作用機序はどのような影響を与えるのでしょうか?
Normal plants we just talked about
先ほどお話しした普通の植物
The more egg fatters it grows, the bigger it grows
卵が太れば増えるほど大きくなる
it's a normal plant
それは普通の植物です
You give it 0.2 a little bit of egg nitrate
0.2の卵硝酸塩を少し加えます
it looks like this
このように見えます
Here are the different blade sizes
各種刃のサイズはこちら
when we give it a high concentration
高濃度に与えると
it increases its output
それは出力を増加させます
But this function is broken
しかし、この機能は壊れています
It has no way to have this growth
これほど成長するわけがない
So it's like talking about the mechanism of power
つまり、権力のメカニズムについて話しているようなものです
reassignment mechanism
再割り当てメカニズム
for its high concentration
濃度が高いため
Increased growth is an important mechanism
成長の促進は重要なメカニズムです
So I just use this
だから私はこれを使うだけです
I also like to grow flowers at home occasionally
たまに家で花を育てるのも好きです
It's hard for me to rethink long
長く考え直すのは難しい
this plant is very interesting
この植物はとても興味深いです
how funny is it
どれくらい面白いですか
as it is now green
今は緑色なので
It turns red when the sun is strong
日差しが強いと赤くなります
so i find it funny
だから面白いと思う
i will cut it off
私はそれを切り取ります
Pull the fork again, let it take root and turn red
もう一度フォークを引くと根がついて赤くなります
Then I planted it in the ground
それから地面に植えました
I am also doing experiments on these three seeds when I go home.
私も家に帰ってからこの３つの種を使って実験をしています。
when i take it off
私がそれを脱ぐとき
It was probably these two leaves
たぶんこの二枚の葉っぱだったはず
I left a big leaf for this one
これには大きな葉っぱを残しておきました
This is actually the same leaf as this
実はこれと同じ葉っぱなんです
do you see the difference
違いがわかりますか
this is their grandson
これは彼らの孫です
This grandson has grown so big
この孫はとても大きくなりました
This grandson is still so young
この孫はまだとても小さいです
So it's different with grandma
だからおばあちゃんとは違うんだよ
I want to say wow
すごいって言いたい
because when i saw this i thought
これを見たときに思ったので
I must take a picture and tell you the story
写真を撮ってその話をしなければなりません
That just goes to show
それはただ示すだけです
Big leaves can grow small leaves
大きな葉は小さな葉に栄養を与えることができます
You would imagine that the big leaf would eat his nutrients
大きな葉が栄養を食べてしまうのではないかと想像するでしょう。
no he will help the little leaves grow
いいえ、彼は小さな葉が成長するのを手伝ってくれるでしょう
So this is good proof
だからこれは良い証拠だよ
I want to say wow this is my proof of theory
これが私の理論の証明だ、と言いたい
exactly such a situation
まさにそのような状況
good
良い
That's a reassignment mechanism
それが再割り当てメカニズムです
There is another mechanism for reassignment
再割り当てには別のメカニズムがあります
Mention here means
ここで言及するということは、
Xiao salt
シャオ塩
In addition to being metabolized
新陳代謝されるだけでなく、
there is another possibility
別の可能性があります
It will be stored in the vacuole
液胞に蓄えられます
In fact, plant cells are very interesting
実は植物細胞はとても興味深いのです
Plant cells are actually filled with vacuoles
植物細胞は実際には液胞で満たされています
It's all vacuoles
全部空胞だよ
Probably the cytoplasm is sieved to a very small size
おそらく細胞質が非常に小さなサイズにふるいにかけられていると思われます
then they
それから彼らは
Xiao acid inflammation can be stored in the vacuole
Xiao酸性炎症は液胞に蓄えられる可能性がある
In fact, they say that inside your plant
実際、工場内では次のように言われています。
For example, now people often say that there is
たとえば、今、よく言われるのが、
Water and plants contain too much acid
水や植物には酸が多すぎる
So they say before eating vegetables
野菜を食べる前に彼らはこう言います
It's better to test whether the amount of Xiao Suinyan is enough
Xiao Suinyanの量が十分であるかどうかをテストすることをお勧めします
In fact, when you measure
実際に測ってみると、
What does Xiao Suinyan measure?
シャオ・スイニャンは何を測定しますか?
The test is the Xiao acid inflammation in the vacuole
検査は液胞内のシャオ酸炎症です
Vacuole
液胞
The vacuole is it's a storage place for it
液胞はそれを保管する場所です
Vacuoles are fun
液胞は楽しい
The vacuole is the plant's storage room
液胞は植物の貯蔵室です
also a trash can
ゴミ箱も
Throw it in where it doesn't want
いらないところに放り込む
It has to be stored and thrown in
保管して投入する必要があります
in this way
この上
That
それか
Xiao Suanyan also threw it in
シャオ・スアンヤンも投げた
Actually they said
実際に彼らはこう言いました
corn did
トウモロコシがやった
they say corn yields
彼らはトウモロコシの収穫量を言う
In fact, it has to do with its ability to store
実際、それはその保存能力に関係しています。
it needs to be able to store
保存できる必要がある
and move it out efficiently
効率的に移動させます
hugging is important
ハグは大事だよ
then we just mentioned
それから、先ほども言いましたが
another 1.7
さらに1.7
Is responsible for grabbing out the storage
ストレージを取得する責任があります
a place to repurpose
再利用する場所
I just said that when the concentration was high outside
外で集中力が高まったときに言ったばかりです
It uses the two golds of 1.11 and 1.12
1.11と1.12の2つの金を使用します
send it to young night piece
ヤングナイトピースに送ってください
When there is no anti-inflammatory outside
外部に抗炎症剤がない場合
how to feed that young man
あの若者にどうやって食事を与えるか
he thought
彼は思った
Lao Ye still has some Xiao Chang Yan stored there
ラオ・イェーにはまだシャオ・チャン・ヤンが保管されている
just that night movie
ちょうどその夜の映画
There's still some left in that night cannon.
あの夜の大砲はまだ残っている。
So he starts another posture at this time
そこで彼はこの時点で別の姿勢を開始します
1.7
１。７
he is in laoye
彼はラオエにいます
just the biggest night movie
まさに最大の夜映画
earthquake eternal strongest
震災永遠最強
Lao Ye is now
ラオ・イェーは今
Old leaves remove excess inflammation
古い葉は過剰な炎症を取り除く
Also by plugging the pipe
パイプを差し込むことによっても
this highway
この高速道路
sent him to young night slices
彼を若い夜のスライスに送ります
to make him grow
彼を成長させるために
good
良い
good so
いいですね
The mechanism of action is different from that
それとは作用機序が違います
it is outside when concentrations are low
濃度が低いときは屋外です
In case there is no way to use the stored
保存したデータを使用できない場合
Sure enough, the concentration outside and the lack of eggs outside
案の定、外の集中と外の卵の不足
It can't grow well
うまく成長できない
That means you're out of pocket.
つまり、お金がないということです。
You can't hurry up and get the money out of the bank
急いで銀行からお金を引き出すことはできない
you are probably hungry
あなたはおそらくお腹が空いているでしょう
So this mechanism is to allow it to transfer the bank's money
つまり、このメカニズムは銀行のお金を送金できるようにするためのものです
Hurry up and get it out again, you can use it
急いでまた取り出して、使えるよ
So you can see the two mechanisms
2 つのメカニズムがわかります
In fact, the same output is to find a way to protect the youngest leaves
実際、同じ出力は、最も若い葉を保護する方法を見つけることです。
make it grow well
元気に育つように
But a different mechanism is activated
しかし、別のメカニズムが作動します
one they send is different
彼らが送ったものは異なります
This is from the root
これは根元からです
That is to say, when the concentration outside is high
つまり、外部の濃度が高いとき
It starts this 1.11 and 1.12
この1.11と1.12から始まります
Let it do the transformation, let it attack the tender leaves
変身させて、若葉を攻撃させて
But when there is nothing about 1.7 outside
でも外に1.7くらい何もないときは
He tried to find a way to capture the old business of storage.
彼はストレージという古いビジネスを取り戻す方法を見つけようとしました。
to feed the young leaves
若葉に餌を与えるために
So these two methods are trying to find a way to feed the young leaves
したがって、これら 2 つの方法は、若い葉に栄養を与える方法を見つけようとしています。
then you want to say
それからあなたは言いたいのですか
But he has to grow himself
でも彼自身も成長しなければならない
why is he feeding young leaves
なぜ彼は若葉を食べているのですか
Actually, I'm going to tell the story about the oldest tree.
実は、一番古い木についての話をしようと思います。
you know it's the oldest tree
それが最古の木であることを知っていますか
4700 year old tree
樹齢4700年の木
then he was alive
それから彼は生きていた
Looks like there are no leaves, he's still alive
葉がないようですが、まだ生きています
In fact, this 4,700-year-old tree
実はこの樹齢4,700年の木は、
They said that when the Golden Branch Pagoda was built
金枝塔が建てられたとき、彼らはこう言いました。
he is a thousand years old
彼は千歳です
why plants live so long
なぜ植物はそんなに長生きするのか
It's the same as the chess piece I just mentioned
先ほどのチェスの駒と同じです
His own survival is not important
彼自身の生存は重要ではない
Actually you see this cell
実際にこの細胞が見えます
Not 4700 year old cells
4700年前の細胞ではない
he is actually his
彼は実際に彼のものです
It is his descendants who are shrunk through
縮こまっていくのは彼の子孫たちだ
so his young leaves are his offspring
だから彼の若葉は彼の子孫だ
That's why he tried his best
だからこそ彼は全力を尽くした
exhaustion strategy
枯渇戦略
Try to send the most nutrients to the young leaves
栄養を最大限に若葉に送り込むようにしましょう
use this old tree to tell you
この古い木を使ってあなたに伝えてください
Why do plants have such a design
なぜ植物にはそのような模様があるのか
In fact, he is trying to find a way to live to at least 4000 water
実際、彼は少なくとも水深4000度まで生き延びる方法を見つけようとしている。
he wishes he still had a part
彼はまだ自分に役割があればよかったのに
So the plant actually has a lot of old cells dead.
つまり、植物には実際には死んだ古い細胞がたくさんあるのです。
But his whole life is maintained
しかし彼の生涯は維持される
He is not the same as the animal design
彼は動物のデザインと同じではありません
Your plants are infinitely reproducible
あなたの植物は無限に再現可能です
And the growth of plants is unlimited
そして植物の成長は無限です
it can...
できる...
It has that reproductive you can...
それはあなたができるその生殖能力を持っています...
you basically go from the shadows when
あなたは基本的に影から遠ざかるとき
just decide your two hands
両手を決めてください
You won't grow three hands again
もう手は3本も生えないよ
different plants
さまざまな植物
Its branch can play infinitely
そのブランチは無限に再生できます
Because the outside environment is different
外の環境が違うから
do all the play
すべての遊びをする
Those few experiments
それらのいくつかの実験
In fact, let us rewrite a sentence in the textbook
実際に教科書の文を書き直してみましょう
what is it
それは何ですか
That is to say, I just said
つまり、今言ったばかりです
There are two pipes in the plant
工場内にはパイプが2本あります
One is wooden cloth, the other is plug tube
1 つは木製の布、もう 1 つはプラグチューブです
In fact, in the textbook
実は教科書には
a famous saying is
有名な言葉は
Xiao Suinyan will only be transported inside the wooden cloth
シャオ・スイニャンは木製の布の中にのみ輸送されます
But the few genes we just
しかし、私たちがたった数個の遺伝子を
There is also a 1.9 that I dont have time to talk about
もう 1.9 がありますが、それについて話す時間がありません
In fact, they are all sealing, relying on sealing to transport
実際、それらはすべて密閉されており、輸送には密閉に依存しています。
And some envelopes, envelopes transport
一部の封筒、封筒の輸送
It has a great influence on the delivery of Xiao acid inflammation
Xiao酸性炎症の発生に大きな影響を与えます
even affect the growth of plants
植物の成長にも影響を与える
So we rewritten Xiao Keshu's sentence
それで私たちはXiao Keshuの文章を書き直しました
should change it
それを変更する必要があります
cloth from the ground up
布を根元から
indeed wooden cloth
まさに木の布
But the plug is to let Xiao Suinyan redistribute
しかし、問題はXiao Suinyanに再配布させることです
a very important mechanism
非常に重要なメカニズム
But also because we have to rewrite the sentence
しかし、文章を書き直さなければならないため、
A classic quote from a textbook
教科書からの古典的な引用
we also suffered
私たちも苦しみました
because at first everyone
なぜなら最初はみんな
Don't even believe our stuff
私たちのものさえ信じないでください
told us to do better than others
私たちに他の人よりも良くやれと言った
twice as many experiments to prove
証明するための実験の数が 2 倍になる
our theory was right
私たちの理論は正しかった
But I believe that today
でも今日はそう信じてる
In these three fits I think already
これら 3 つの適合性では、すでにそう思います
write this sentence down
この文を書き留めてください
ok today
はい、今日
Today I speak a little fast, that's about it.
今日は少し早口で話しますが、それだけです。
The last possible thanks to the research team in our laboratory
私たちの研究室の研究チームに最後まで感謝します
I probably wrote it just now
たぶん今書いたんだけど
A place for each job who does it
それを行うそれぞれの仕事のための場所
And the support from Academia Sinica and the Ministry of Science and Technology
中央研究院と科学技術省の支援
And most importantly thank you all
そして最も重要なことは、皆さんに感謝することです
so late to listen
聞くのがとても遅くなりました
Thanks
ありがとう
that's brilliant
そりゃ素晴らしい
I used to be the one who memorized that wrong church book concept
かつて私はその間違った教会の本の概念を暗記していた人でした
Now it's an eye-opener
今では目を見張るものがあります
This one is actually very important.
これは実際には非常に重要です。
I used to study zoology in Taiwan
私は台湾で動物学を勉強していました
Mr. Cai is studying Botany
蔡さんは植物学を勉強しています
Our Department of Zoology and Department of Plants are both managed by No. 1
私たちの動物学科と植物学科はどちらもNo.1によって管理されています。
So we used to joke
それで私たちはよく冗談を言っていました
we all eat them
私たちは皆それを食べます
animal eats pig
動物吃豬
result you see
見た結果
we are all eaten
私たちは皆食べられています
If plants could live to be 4,000 years old
もし植物が4000年まで生きられるとしたら
None of our animals live to be 4,000 years old
私たちの動物には4,000歳まで生きる動物はいません
But today is really exciting
でも今日は本当に素晴らしいです
and
と
This also tells us that a very in-depth scientific research
これはまた、非常に綿密な科学的研究が行われたことを示しています。
How to overthrow the authoritative statement
権威ある声明をどう覆すか
That is science is continuous progress
つまり科学は進歩し続けているということです
That human wisdom is constantly accumulating
人間の知恵は常に蓄積されているということ
The results of these researches are all his.
これらの研究結果はすべて彼のものです。
Teacher Cais guidance is also done by colleagues in the laboratory
蔡先生の指導は研究室の同僚たちも行っています
pretty brilliant
かなり素晴らしい
I am very happy to learn new knowledge after listening
聞いて新しい知識を知ることができてとても嬉しいです
Well, now we still have some time to ask you some questions.
さて、まだ時間がありますので、いくつか質問させていただきます。
I don't know if you have any questions to ask
何か質問があるか分かりませんが、
Am I here to ask a simple question that says
私がここに来たのは、次のような単純な質問をするためですか？
So if we know that these genes may be related to
したがって、これらの遺伝子が関連している可能性があることがわかっている場合、
this a delayed this
これはこれを遅らせました
Words related to the Suanyan lawsuit
スアンヤン訴訟に関連する言葉
In agriculture, we may be within the scope of application
農業においても応用範囲に入るかもしれません
what might be the benefit
何のメリットがあるのでしょう
So I just wanted to say that actually
だから本当はそれが言いたかっただけなんです
There are two directions to increase the utilization efficiency of eggs
卵の利用効率を上げるには2つの方向性がある
One is when the egg fat is low
一つは、卵の脂肪が少ない場合です。
it can grow well
それはよく成長することができます
At this time it may be called
現時点ではそう呼ばれるかもしれません
It's just a function
それは単なる関数です
Strengthen it to utilize the stored anti-inflammatory
蓄積された抗炎症物質を利用するためにそれを強化します。
In fact, their farmers are fat
実際、彼らの農民は太っている
It's not like fertilizing every day
毎日肥料を与えるわけではありません
It actually threw a lot of fertilizer into it.
実際には大量の肥料を投入しました。
Then let it eat for a while and then add fertilizer
しばらく食べさせてから肥料を与えます。
So they actually have to be stored very quickly
したがって、実際には非常に迅速に保存する必要があります
then let it flow
それから流れに任せて
so we can strengthen it this storage
このストレージを強化できます
A word of ability to reuse
再利用能力の一言
may allow the plants to grow well
植物がうまく成長できるようになるかもしれない
it's a mechanism
それは仕組みです
Or it can increase growth when egg fat is high
または、卵の脂肪が多い場合には成長を促進する可能性があります
At this time, I used the function of eleven eleven and twelve just now.
この時、先ほどのeleven eleven and twelveの機能を使いました。
so there is probably no way we can do a dozen birds
ですから、十数羽の鳥を作ることはおそらく不可能です
just one way to solve it all
すべてを解決するたった一つの方法
It may be necessary to design low egg fat at different times
さまざまなタイミングで卵脂肪を低く設計する必要がある場合があります
There are different ways to use when egg fat is high
卵脂肪が多い場合のさまざまな使用方法があります
good
良い
do you have any questions
何か質問がありますか
Don't ask Mr. Cai today
今日は蔡氏に質問しないでください
here first
まずはここで
here's the green one press down
こちらが緑色のボタンを押してください
on the microphone
マイクで
Thank you, I am also very interested in agricultural applications
ありがとう、私も農業応用にとても興味があります
just mentioned
先ほど述べた
When the land was light
大地が明るかった頃
seems to add one
1つ追加されるようです
still lead me to forget
まだ私を忘れさせます
if that's the case isn't it
そうだとしたらそうじゃないですか
If, for example, a relatively flat disease
たとえば、比較的平坦な病気の場合、
inside the land
土地の中で
but if its
しかし、もしそれなら
A still just talked about it
Aはまだそれについて話したばかりです
if it is higher
それが高い場合
the agricultural production
農業生産
still available in
まだ入手可能です
under low circumstances
低い状況下で
same high yield
同じ高出力
so is that so
そうですか
actually
実際
Dan Lin Jia balance is the best
ダン・リン・ジアのバランスが最高です
you have one more
もう 1 つあります
it can't take advantage of
それは活用できない
so they have to balance
だから彼らはバランスを取る必要がある
well balanced
バランスの取れた
that so
まあまあ
just said
今言いました
He said that the ground egg fertilizer needs egg and armor
粉砕卵の肥料には卵と鎧が必要だと彼は言いました
In fact, no matter how low or high
実際、どんなに低くても高くても
You have to match enough
十分に一致させる必要があります
That zero heel
あのゼロヒール
it can grow normally
普通に成長できるよ
Just now you talked about a low-definition joint force
今、あなたは低解像度の統合軍について話しました。
yes
はい
That is the Qingheli
それがチンヘリです
That's not a problem with Egg Zero
エッグゼロならそんな問題ないよ
It's antiacid
抗酸薬です
Low-definition joint force and advanced
低解像度の関節力と高度な
zero egg
卵ゼロ
right
右
zero acidification
零酸化
Zero Acidification Is Another Thing
酸性化ゼロは別問題
that is a protein modification
それはタンパク質の修飾です
content with zero
ゼロの内容
In fact, it is not so directly related.
実際には、それほど直接的な関係はありません。
that is a protein modification
それはタンパク質の修飾です
The modification of the protein
タンパク質の修飾
Could it be related to the content of zero?
ゼロの内容と関係があるのでしょうか？
should not be so directly related
それほど直接的に関係するべきではない
In fact, the content of zero should be enough
実際にはゼロの内容で十分です
do this thing
このことをする
Zero actually has other places
ゼロには実は別の場所がある
there will be a shortage
不足するでしょう
OK
OK
not because of
のせいではない
there is a problem here
ここに問題があります
the question i just asked
私がたった今した質問
I told that lady just now
私は今その女性に言いました
a little bit like
少し似ています
because of ourselves
自分たちのせいで
I'm growing vegetables, I'm not a science guy
私は野菜を育てていますが、科学者ではありません
the one who actually grows vegetables
実際に野菜を育てている人
But I will find out that
しかし、私はそれを知るでしょう
If I can actually activate the latter graph
実際に後者のグラフをアクティブにできれば
Because just now there are two pictures
今のところ写真が2枚あるので
One picture is after adding the cake
1枚の写真はケーキを追加した後です
Immediately there will be a good growth effect
すぐに良い成長効果が現れます
but soon fell down
しかしすぐに倒れてしまいました
The other one can start another
他の人は別のことを始めることができます
slowly coming up
ゆっくりと上がってくる
Yes, but its later plateau effect
はい、しかしその後のプラトー効果
would be better
のほうがいい
then we would think to say
それなら私たちはこう言うことを考えます
If so, the fat I added in front
もしそうなら、私が前に追加した脂肪
If this graph
このグラフなら
That is only a short-lived effect
それは一時的な効果にすぎません
Then I might be quick, yes.
それなら早いかもしれません、はい。
but i can't
でもできない
If it grows for a long time
長く育てれば
Then maybe I can't achieve my effect
それでは効果が得られないかもしれません
Then the graph behind
次に、後ろのグラフィック
I can use a small amount of fertilizer
肥料は少量で大丈夫です
But I can achieve better results
しかし、私はより良い結果を達成することができます
If I say I hope to be able to achieve
達成できればいいと言ったら
when this effect
この効果があるとき
I can't figure it out yet
まだわかりません
teacher what you study
先生は何を勉強していますか
How to combine it with our food
料理との組み合わせ方
Okay, you just answered earlier
わかりました、先ほど答えましたね
when it's a problem
問題があるとき
we do
私たちはそうします
when planting
植えるとき
I do it first in the land
その土地で最初にやります
Basic fertilizer
基礎肥
Just do soil improvement first
まずは土壌改良をしましょう
Manure, chicken manure, I made it first
肥料、鶏糞、私が最初に作りました
Then after planting
そして植えた後は
I take a while and then start adding fertilizer
しばらく時間を置いてから肥料を加え始めます
So our current experience is not enough to judge
したがって、私たちの現在の経験だけでは判断するのに十分ではありません
I always ask people how long it takes to start adding
私はいつも追加を開始するまでにどれくらい時間がかかるかを人々に尋ねます
Is it liquid fertilizer or solid fertilizer?
液体肥料ですか、それとも固形肥料ですか？
How long is the effect of liquid fertilizer? How long is the effect of solid fertilizer?
液肥の効果はどれくらいですか? 固形肥料の効果はどれくらいですか?
But it feels like what the teacher heard tonight
でもそれは先生が今夜聞いたことのように感じます
It seems that I can't cut it all at once.
一気には切れないようです。
Have you come to cut it up? Yes
切りに来たんですか? はい
then i meant to say
それから私は言うつもりだった
let me listen
聞かせてください
Because Xiao Suanyan has been in the Grandfather Alliance
シャオ・スアンヤンは祖父同盟に参加しているため
They've been talking about this
彼らはこのことについて話していました
is a self-cancer factor
自己発がん因子です
what about the people we are planting
私たちが植えている人々はどうですか
I can think about how to mix my fertilizer
肥料の配合方法を考えることができる
or how to get wet in time
または時間内に濡れる方法
or control over dosage
または用量管理
Can achieve the effect that the teacher wants to say
教師の言いたい効果を実現できる
able to produce that output and quality
その出力と品質を生み出すことができる
but i don't want to have
でも私は持ちたくない
For example, Xiao acid inflammation over treatment
たとえば、Xiao 酸性炎症の治療
participate in the plant
工場に参加する
or the problem of loss in nature
あるいは自然の喪失の問題
Well actually I just said
そうですね、実は今言ったばかりです
I heard someone say that actually a lot
誰かが実際にそう言うのをよく聞きました
Do a lot of bad things for a while
しばらく悪いことをたくさんしてください
yes
はい
In fact, it is a water trafficker
実は水商売です
pay less, give slowly
支払いは少なく、ゆっくり与えてください
but
しかし
It's a waste of time, right?
時間の無駄ですよね？
Because the announcement did not go in
アナウンスが入ってなかったので
Go find the announcement and do the strength work
お知らせを見つけて筋力トレーニングをしましょう
that's a problem
それは問題だ
if we can
できれば
Therefore, Tang Wanjin's private lending
したがって、唐万進の私的な融資は、
Fertilizers are sometimes slow consumption
肥料の消費が遅い場合がある
flow out slowly
ゆっくりと流れ出る
So this slow consumption
つまり、この消費の遅さは
It is actually a comparison
実際の比較です
complex fertilizer
複合肥料
make it easy to go
行きやすいようにする
that graded fertilizer
その等級の肥料
Grading slowly
ゆっくり採点
That's actually
それは実際に
no matter how slow it is too late
どんなに遅くても遅すぎる
it will
そうなる
will grow fast
早く成長します
Then you just mentioned
それからあなたは今言いました
we can only control us
私たちは私たちをコントロールすることしかできません
Eat the amount of product you want to eliminate
除去したい量の製品を食べる
Well, you can try it
まあ、試してみてもいいでしょう
at different times of day
一日のさまざまな時間帯に
Consumer Products Let's do it another day
消費者向け製品 別の日にしましょう
I was told it was
そうだと言われました
Help manage consumer products
消費者向け製品の管理を支援する
should be
あるべきです
But in fact, life in Taiwan is long
でも実は台湾での生活は長いんです
more funny
もっと面白いです
so
それで
it will be really tiring
本当に疲れるだろう
do you think this is the way to act
これが行動の仕方だと思いますか
because there's another joke
別の冗談があるから
it's us
それは私たちです
because we are smiles
私たちは笑顔だから
if you don't call
電話しなかったら
Sometimes someone else steals you
時々、他の人があなたを盗むことがあります
In fact, there is a concern
実は懸念もある
Because the plant that lives at night
夜に生きる植物だから
If you don't have it, it's not easy to save
持っていない場合、保存するのは簡単ではありません
just let the body feel
ただ体に感じさせてください
I like this
私はこれが好き
so
それで
it's hard
それは難しい
But because doing is not dynamic
しかし、行動は動的ではないので、
so it's kind of strategic
ある意味戦略的ですね
I mean, actually you have to check the time in the morning too.
つまり、朝は時間を確認する必要があります。
unless it's very very early in the afternoon
午後のかなり早い時間でない限り
Otherwise, it will be collected later
それ以外の場合は後で回収されます
If we strap it up
ストラップを締めたら
Yes, it will be easier to get tired
はい、疲れやすくなります
morning dish
朝の料理
Take it because it gets hot
暑いから取ってね
if we charge
請求したら
If you want to receive 7 and then come and take it home
7を受け取って持ち帰りたい場合は、
After it gets hot, the coconut will be there soon
暑くなったらココナッツもすぐに出てくるよ
actually some
実際にはいくつか
the more experienced stuff
もっと経験のある人
like i just said
先ほど言ったように
Yellowing occurs when eggs are absent
卵がなくなると黄色くなる
or start hard
それとも一生懸命始めるか
if you have enough experience
十分な経験があれば
You might be able to use these factors to climb out
これらの要素を利用して這い上がることができるかもしれません
it is missing egg in it
卵が入っていない
of course
もちろん
I once had someone talk to
ある人に話しかけてもらったことがある
let the food tell you it's missing eggs
卵が足りないことを食べ物に教えてもらいましょう
Then there are also people who are doing experiments like this
では、こんな実験をしている人もいるのですね。
What you are doing now is actually lack of water.
私たちが今起きていることは、実は水不足なのです。
Actually because of water
実は水のせいで
water is also a factor
水も要因です
it's gonna give it a finish or something
それはそれを終わらせるか何かを与えるでしょう
so when it lacks water
だから水分が不足すると
there will be a green
緑があるだろう
let you see the colors
色を見てみましょう
This is the kind of slippery
これは滑りやすいタイプです
So someone was thinking about this method
そこで誰かがこの方法を考えました
but i think
しかし、私は思います
or realistically don't go
あるいは現実的には行かない
Everyone has another question
誰もが別の質問を持っています
Dr. Cai
カイ博士
Because this speech can be heard
このスピーチが聞こえるから
It's a pity for Dr. Cai
蔡博士は残念だ
We now have more practical questions from the audience
聴衆からより実践的な質問が寄せられました
It's a serious meal today
今日は本格的な食事です
we ate this today
私たちは今日これを食べました
Everyone wants to buy an organic one
誰もがオーガニックのものを買いたいと思っています
OK that one is not allowed
OK、それは許可されていません
Some people on the Internet say that water and juice are bothersome
ネットでは水やジュースが面倒という声も
What does he learn from others to guarantee?
彼は保証するために他の人から何を学びますか？
organic failure
有機不機
But he still can't eat
でも彼はまだ食べられない
I still feel dangerous
まだ危険を感じています
I responded with
私はこう答えました
It's like just talking about water and juice
ただ水とジュースについて話しているようなものです
He still needs to protect the glue in the water
彼はまだ水の中の接着剤を保護する必要があります
It's like the one that just took a picture of me being honest
正直な私を写真に撮ったあの人のように
I still hold you and eat alone
私はまだあなたを抱いて一人で食事をします
In fact, I recently said that I would help you provide
実際、私は最近、あなたが提供するのを手伝うと言いました
so that
となることによって
This is not the case, in fact, this is not drinkable
そんなことはありません、実はこれは飲めません
I think it's good to try
試してみるのもいいと思います
not too high
高すぎない
Actually don't be too...
実際にはそうならないでください...
still eat alone
まだ一人で食べる
I don't know
わからない
for sure
確かに
In fact, traffic actors will pick it up
実際、交通犯罪者がそれを拾うでしょう
But everyone is too all reaction
でもみんな反応が良すぎる
horse british
馬 イギリス人
In fact, traffic actors are going to be big
実際、交通関連のアクターは大きくなるだろう
Traffic actor enters into the body
交通行為者が体内に侵入
he can also be in the body
彼は体の中にいることもできる
at the scene
在現場
So the right amount of community is solidarity is OK
つまり、適切な量のコミュニティがあれば連帯感は問題ない
It's not that everyone is participating
全員が参加しているわけではない
each roughly first
それぞれ大まかに最初に
so
それで
Great amount for your facility
あなたの施設に最適な金額
and often eat
そしてよく食べる
occasionally followed by
時々続いて
brother is delicious
お兄さんは美味しい
For example, I went to follow
たとえば、私はフォローに行きました
Internet people they are eating
彼らが食べているインターネットの人々
that
それか
Ma Dongxie
馬東謝
will suck
それを吸うことができます
miss children
子供たちが恋しい
that's all good food
それはすべておいしい食べ物です
so equivalent to
とても同等です
good water will flow
良い水が流れます
will be great
素晴らしいでしょう
that's a lot
それは多いです
but i usually
でも私は普段
probably won't affect
おそらく影響はないだろう
Adults think of children when they eat
大人は子どものことを考えて食事をする
Give me a hug, I still dont have a car to eat
抱きしめて、まだ食べる車がない
Ask Dean
ディーンに聞いてください
The movie that teaches the teacher to laugh is
先生に笑い方を教える映画は「나」です
on the water with saw
鋸で水の上に
On the road is a well-known airport
道路上には有名な空港があります
still early on the ground
まだ地上では早い段階で
but i was surprised not to see
でも見なかったことに驚いた
Physically, this is the surface of the water
物理的には、これは水の表面です
lots of flattening
たくさんの平ら化
that's it
それでおしまい
the elegant
エレガントな
painted flat
平らに塗装された
That is to say, the sandy water
つまり砂水です
If it's just oily smoke
ただの油煙なら
you have to watch early
早く見なければなりません
right
右
In fact, to be measured
実際にテストされるのは
Oh flat
ああ、フラット
Is it really slippery?
本当に滑りやすいのでしょうか？
Tuping also because it has two copies
2枚あるのでチューピングも
four cattle possible
四牛可能
elegant water
エレガントな水
So in fact Tuping was very early
つまり、実際のところ、Tuping は非常に早かったのです
right
右
that's the time
それがその時です
Death will probably be earlier together
おそらく死は一緒に早まるだろう
maximum
最大
painted flat
平らに塗装された
because I saw
見たから
Some people are over there, fishing casually there, it's so hard
あそこに何人かがいて、そこで何気なく釣りをしている、とても難しい
Many people seem to spend a lot of time, what are they doing?
多くの人が多くの時間を費やしているようですが、何をしていますか？
Others you cause this level of care
あなたがこのレベルの苦痛を引き起こしている他の人たち
I just said that because it has not absorbed people from the important places, it will go down
大事なところから人を吸収してないから下がるって言っただけだよ
from to level, from to elsewhere
レベルから、他の場所へ
In fact, you see, the ditch next to the heavy foundation, sometimes we all say, you see the ditch
実際、ほら、重い基礎の隣に溝があります、時々私たちは皆、「溝が見えます」と言います
So there is no way to prevent it, I just said not to pass the time
だから防ぐ方法はない、ただ時間を潰すなと言っただけだ
Now people don't understand, don't waste time
今では人々は理解できません、時間を無駄にする必要はありません
Then it is easier for me to think of a solution, and I will think about it in the rest of the time
そうすれば解決策を考えやすくなるので、残りの時間で考えます
Thanks
ありがとう
OK, let's do it later
わかりました、後でやります
thank you sir
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much Mayor, today I am a cat
市長、ありがとうございます、今日は猫です
This one selling clothes is our export from Kelan
この衣類を販売しているのはケランからの輸出品です
Is it called a temple in our two countries?
私たちの両国ではそれは寺院と呼ばれますか？
I've always been done, sometimes doing the same old things
私はいつも終わっていて、時々同じ古いことをしている
Then, Yangmei just now, you know what it is
では、ヤンメイ、今、それが何であるか知っていますか？
NPK here today, you know I was originally
今日はNPKがここにいます、私がかつてそうであったことを知っていますか
I'm not an easy expert
私は簡単な専門家ではありません
So it's too late for me to be today
それでは今日はもう手遅れです
That's it, and NPK
それはそれで、NPK
What crop are you looking at?
どの作物を見ていますか？
Then NPK needs to match, what is this?
次に、NPK が一致する必要がありますが、これは何ですか?
The organization to match is Unit A.
対戦する編成はユニットAです。
Then I only have a visit today
それでは今日は訪問のみです
I used to be a high-speed flying pulse, I don't understand
昔は高速飛行パルスだったんだ、分からない
What is this output, what is this output?
この出力は何ですか、この出力は何ですか?
It was for your face
それはあなたの顔のためでした
Mostly Classroom Classroom Years
ほとんどが教室での授業期間
is the classroom
教室です
In fact, this contains the classroom
実はこの中に教室が入っています
In fact, many classrooms take the form of classrooms
実際、多くの教室は教室の形をしています。
in the age of jurisprudence
法学の時代に
It is a classroom where strength can beat
力が勝つ教室です
also very rich place
とても豊かな場所でもあります
For the Taiwan market
台湾市場向け
I almost government the entire Taiwan market
台湾市場全体をほぼ統治している
Exclusive loans are on the market
独占的なローンが市場に出ています
Is it the only reason
それだけが理由ですか
Moreover, the Taiwan Committee is ruled by law
さらに、台湾委員会は法律によって支配されています
Taiwan committee members are also similar to us
台湾の委員も私たちと同じです
with american representatives
アメリカの代表者たちと
science done
科学は終わった
So if we're going to step in
それで、私たちが介入するつもりなら
I heard it's hard to do
難しいと聞きました
Actually there is another problem
実は別の問題がある
we also talk about
私たちも話します
The cultural position of Taiwan and the mainland
台湾と大陸の文化的地位
government for agriculture
農業のための政府
easy replenishment is
簡単な補充は
mention to others
他の人に言及する
That's actually a very hurtful thing
それは実はとても傷つくことなのです
so that no comparison
比べられないように
nest pressure problem
巣の圧力の問題
current continent
現在的大陸
they also have
彼らも持ってる
this
これ
this is miserable
これは悲惨だ
it's a big chicken
それは大きな鶏です
Normally I might do something like this satellite
通常はこの衛星のようなことをするかもしれません
it's very very little frame
とても小さなフレームです
So make a market
それで市場を作る
It's fine
大丈夫だよ
only in domestic countries
国内のみで
Chugoku University
中国大附
now it's like this
今はこんな感じです
that's what it sanctioned
それが認可したことだ
now also in the country
今では国内にもあります
Special medical treatment will not
特別な医療は受けられません
thank you
ありがとう
come here
ここに来て
we also feel alike
私たちも同じように感じます
another report
別のレポート
us
私たち
To my own teacher here
ここの私の先生へ
our own professor
私たち自身の教授
Dr. Cai
カイ博士
thank you
ありがとう
very deep showing
非常に深い表現
Very interesting and wonderful presentation
とても興味深く素晴らしいプレゼンテーション
the layman who listened to me listened
私の話を聞いた一般人は聞いた
I feel I have learned a lot
たくさんのことを学んだ気がします
Your research is a thing with patterns
あなたの研究にはパターンがあるものです
Arab world
アラブ世界
I don't know
わからない
The conclusion of the year is for other duties
一年の締めくくりはその他の業務のため
For example, a big tree is flat like a red block
たとえば、大きな木は赤いブロックのように平らです
Or Xiaocaoruqiu sea sugar can be tried together
またはXiaocaoruqiu海糖を一緒に試すことができます
In fact, we young people
実は、私たち若者は、
No pattern after error
エラー後のパターンなし
But many people even create waterways
しかし、多くの人は水路さえ作ります
Luck also loads something like
運も次のようなものをロードします
that is
あれは
you know this time we are in apoya province
今回は私たちがアポヤ県にいるのはご存知でしょう
haven't found out yet
まだ分​​かりません
in which issue
どの号で
There must be a large portion
かなりの部分があるはずです
So it's okay to say we are using
したがって、使用していると言っても大丈夫です
he made the basis
彼は基礎を作った
up to now
今まで
many places
多くの場所
Probably the same basic process
おそらく基本的なプロセスは同じだと思います
So this job is the same
だからこの仕事も同じだ
Memory is the same process
記憶も同じプロセスです
Yes, about the same
はい、ほぼ同じです
also a lot of process
工程も多くて
not specifically
具体的にはありません
Only Master Apo uses this method
この方法を使用するのはマスター Apo だけです
should be
あるべきです
the so-called mass
いわゆる大衆
More or less the basic way to try
多かれ少なかれ基本的な試し方
Thanks
ありがとう
no one is doing that
誰もそんなことやってないよ
Traces of research and development
研究開発の跡
I just said this
私はちょうどこれを言いました
different countries
さまざまな国
Different things from Xiaoying Dalai
シャオイン・ダライとの違い
that's interesting
それは面白い
So it is possible that when turned into a crop
したがって、作物に変えられると、
Then put this instead
それなら代わりにこれを入れてください
No need to bring consumption to simultaneous
消費を同時に行う必要はない
Please send this password to the same time
このパスワードを同時に送信してください
In order to make the crop yield reach or how
作物の収量をどのように達成するか
so all crops
だからすべての作物
In the same way, send that classic to the same time
同じように、あのクラシックを同じ時代に送りましょう
That's what I heard
それが私が聞いた話です
sorry
ごめん
Because we are interested in Youqing Rongye
ヨウチン・ロンイェに興味があるから
like to have some
いくつか食べたいです
Just interested in Youqing Rongye
Youqing Rongye に興味があるだけです
There is a natural imitation in Youqing Rongye
Youqing Rongye には自然の模倣があります
it is almost
それはほとんどです
don't send at the same time
同時に送信しないでください
In order to make the crop yield reach or how
作物の収量をどのように達成するか
so all crops
だからすべての作物
In the same way, send that classic to the same time
同じように、あのクラシックを同じ時代に送りましょう
it's almost not the same
ほとんど同じではありません
otherwise no need
それ以外の場合は必要ありません
Obesity
肥満
i think two problems
2つの問題があると思います
That is, can it be in this tree?
つまり、この木に存在できるでしょうか？
can also grow to more
さらに成長することもできます
very natural
特別自然
Spend the day on that tree
その木の上で一日を過ごしてください
to find more high-definition zygote proteins
より高解像度の受精卵タンパク質を見つけるには
Then the second is body fat
続いて2つ目は体脂肪です
if it doesn't need medicine
薬が必要なければ
Even if it is HD fit
HDフィットでも
How did its eggs come from?
その卵はどうやって生まれたのでしょうか？
This is after our trip here
これはここへの旅行の後です
So so the alcohol concentration method it's called is against the North
つまり、そのアルコール濃縮法は北朝鮮に反するということだ
To the north is that some mainland Chinese Xi Jinping is merciful.
北では、中国本土の習近平の一部が慈悲深いということだ。
That's when organic plants continental their generation remains
それは、有機植物が大陸にその世代を残すときです
maybe income
たぶん収入
So those comparisons are still
したがって、それらの比較はまだ続いています
Then it seems to be slowly
それからはゆっくりみたいです
There are also poisonous makeup bacteria, which are slower to exchange
交換が遅い有毒なメイクバクテリアも存在します。
Then your chronic process of dealing with North
それから北との慢性的な付き合い方
it will be compare
比較されるだろう
Won't cause problems with the tablet
タブレットなら問題ないよ
because it flows out slowly like this
こうやってゆっくり流れ出てくるから
So this place will be more than a lot of disappointment
したがって、この場所は多くの失望を招くでしょう
There is a concentrated method
集中法がある
it's totally right and no need
それは完全に正しいし、その必要はない
It doesn't need to be on the legs either, it just doesn't work at all
脚に付ける必要もありません、まったく機能しません
So I thought to myself, because it's totally useless
それで私は思いました、それはまったく役に立たないからです
But in the natural concentration, I don't know what's in it
でも自然濃度では何が入っているのか分からない
increased oxygen together
一緒に酸素を増やします
Organic Concentrate is made with Organic Pair of Legs is a lot
オーガニックコンセントレートはオーガニックペアレッグで作られています
But there is a special
しかし、特別なものがあります
Nothing compares, nor oxygen plus
比較できるものはなく、酸素プラスも
not necessarily, but
必ずしもではありませんが、
Gaga has this, yes, yes, Gaga has this
ガガはこれを持っています、はい、はい、ガガはこれを持っています
After all, but I mean, their claim is
結局のところ、つまり、彼らの主張は次のとおりです
pan natural because it's always close to eating
いつも食べるそばだからパンナチュラル
You also have a way to make it feed me
私に餌を与える方法もあります
that , their ubiquinone
それ、彼らのユビキノン
it pan it pan basically
基本的にパンします
The most pan, if you don't make you full, it will explode
鍋が一番多い、いっぱいにしないと破裂するよ
go all the way, there is a way
ずっと行ってください、道はあります
That is to say, as a filter manure
つまり濾過肥料として
If we cant talk about the fertilizer filter, what about the fertilizer filter?
肥料フィルターについて話せないなら、肥料フィルターはどうなるでしょうか?
It's relatively light bucket shell, yes
比較的軽いバケットシェルです、はい
The chlorine rate of the bucket shell is added to the
バケットシェルの塩素率が加算されます。
This is, really can
これ、本当にできるんです
My burqa's writing, burqa's writing, sorry for my typing
私のブルカの文章、ブルカの文章、タイプしてごめんなさい
In addition to using green manure, it will use the way of turning
緑肥の使用に加えて、転作という方法を使用します。
do it with repost, blame it inside the photo of the business itself
再投稿して、ビジネス自体の写真の中にそれを非難してください
will use the switch to do different things, and then it will, that is,
スイッチを使用して別のことを行うと、次のようになります。
It is what you have harvested by yourself, and only harvested
それはあなたが自分で収穫したものであり、収穫したものだけです
just break it down inside
ただ内部で分解してください
Unless that is to say, you eat part of it, and the rest will be discussed
それがそうでない限り、あなたはそれの一部を食べ​​て、残りは議論されます
then how did you experience this
それで、あなたはこれをどのように経験しましたか
You will also give me my cloth paper, but I still need to give it to you
私の布紙もくれますが、まだ必要です
OK, I want to come, J.M.
わかりました、行きたいです、J.M.
teacher, i want to ask
先生、聞きたいのですが
Because if you hear people say that plants are absorbing egg coal
なぜなら、植物が卵の石炭を吸収していると人々が言うのを聞いたら、
Afterwards it will utilize because it is a sugar principle
砂糖原理なので後は活用します
So it plays because it's the cleaning type of the printer
プリンターのクリーニングタイプなので再生されます
So it will be played, so it will cause a sudden frost
それで遊ぶので、突然の霜を引き起こすでしょう
Wouldn't that job bring him back to something practical?
その仕事は彼を現実的なことに戻すことになるのではないだろうか？
In fact, no one was in private just now
実際、今は誰もプライベートにいませんでした
Will An Nian and Mr. Xiao be the opposite?
アンニアンとシャオ氏は逆になるでしょうか？
Mr. Xiao will turn Liu Brown's words into love stories
シャオ氏はリウ・ブラウンの言葉をラブストーリーに変えるだろう
An Nian will make him make noise
アン・ニアンは騒がしくなるだろう
So in fact, An and Mr. Xiao are the best situation when they are in balance.
つまり、実際のところ、アン氏とシャオ氏はバランスが取れているときが最高の状況なのです。
So will he put his mind back again?
それで彼は再び心を取り戻すでしょうか？
he won't go let him not walk back
彼は行かない、戻らないようにしてください
In fact, the job has been scalding the cleaning place
実際、その仕事で清掃場所が火傷を負っています
A job is something that is always getting to know a good person
仕事は常に良い人と知り合うものです
But the job has been doing this
しかし、仕事はこれを行っています
You try to get the screen's shirk is very low
画面の傾きを非常に低くする方法がわかりました
In fact, the job has been doing such a thing
実際、仕事はそのようなことを行っています
that is coming to his own friend
それは彼自身の友人のところに来る
then discuss with him
それから彼と話し合ってください
What if his Energy and his lover
もし彼のエネルギーと彼の恋人がいたらどうなるでしょうか？
Then Zhou Xiang prays for blessings, will he have to put it back all the time?
それから周翔は祝福を祈りますが、彼はそれをずっと元に戻さなければなりませんか？
But because everything just said has to be absorbed
でも今言ったことはすべて吸収しなければならないから
All the absorption of the two copies is based on the difference in the rank of the pro's name to absorb the two copies.
2 つのコピーの吸収はすべて、2 つのコピーを吸収するプロ名のランクの差に基づいています。
so he doesn't have a pro name on the outside
だから彼は表向きにはプロとしての名前を持っていない
He wants to suck both of them and can't get in
彼は2つすべてをしゃぶるつもりだ、そして彼は入ることができないだろう
The case of octagon on PHC
PHCの八角形の場合
that has lucky growth
幸運な成長を遂げたもの
it looks like it's over
終わったようだ
it's like acting
それは演技のようだ
He just performs what he is usually pointed out to be better
彼は通常、より優れていると指摘されることを実行しているだけです
In fact, it has become a benefit
実はそれがメリットになっている
In fact, you just don't let him become a benefit
実際のところ、あなたは彼を利益にさせてはいけません
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
here
ここ
Learned
学んだ
Ask for today's speech in China
中国での今日のスピーチを依頼する
the teacher learned a lot
先生はたくさんのことを学びました
so i have two questions
それで質問が2つあります
The first question was just about a
最初の質問はちょうど
a director with a fake
偽物を持った監督
Musbu and firmware are not good
ムスブとファームウェアが良くない
We know musbu he includes the director and the fake director
ムスブには監督と偽監督が含まれていることを私たちは知っています
His mind is a housekeeper
彼の心は家政婦です
Hold the air under the country's top work
国内最高の仕事で空気を保つ
Let Ren Ti continue to screen out the three-phase package
Ren Ti に三相パッケージの排除を続けてもらいましょう
he got two copies
彼はコピーを2冊持っていました
Talk about a very important future that may change the content of Taiwan's textbooks
台湾の教科書の内容を変えるかもしれない非常に重要な未来について語る
I want to say earn this deeply
これを深く稼いで言いたい
He has mentioned that the local firefighters were redistributed to
彼は地元の消防士が再配分されたと述べた。
stuffed learning
詰め込み学習
Then this is in the textbook
じゃあ教科書に載ってるよ
This paragraph is not mentioned in the high school textbook
この部分は高校の教科書には載っていない
is that possible
それは可能ですか
In the next few years, with the influence of Dr. Cai
数年後、蔡博士の影響で
This report of the study says eight seconds in the international
この研究報告書によると、国際時間では8秒です。
Take this section of Taiwan's high school biology
台湾の高校生物のこのセクションを受講してください
make a stuffed
ぬいぐるみを作る
this is my first question
これが私の最初の質問です
second question
2番目の質問
pH
pH
Will the acidity and alkalinity of Tulao and its temperature affect
トゥーラオの酸性とアルカリ性、温度は影響しますか
ideas it absorbs
吸収するアイデア
affect this
これに影響を与える
Quiet Firefighter's change in this amount
静かな消防士はこの金額でお釣りが来る
right
右
will affect
影響するだろう
So you have to test the pH of Tu Lao first.
したがって、最初にトゥラオのpHをテストする必要があります。
then do its research
それから研究をしてください
Thanks
ありがとう
I'm wasting questions
質問を無駄にしてる
Is there a textbook that can transform Taiwan
台湾を変える教科書はあるのか
I took a textbook and wrote a textbook
教科書を持ってきて、教科書を書きました
I wrote it in about three or four years
3～4年くらいかけて書きました
Thanks
ありがとう
but my own body
でも自分の体は
count well
よく数える
the size of a person
人の大きさ
we had something here before
以前ここで何かがありました
until the next is forward out
次が出るまで
That's not likely to change in the next few years
それは今後数年は変わらないだろう
Because Dr. Cai has done a lot of research internationally
蔡博士は国際的に多くの研究を行っているため
should be funded by teaching in Taiwan
台湾での教育によって資金を賄うべきである
should accept it
それを受け入れるべきです
put forward wrong ideas
間違った考えを提案する
Japanese teach biology in high school
日本人は高校で生物を教える
So your teaching takes into consideration 30 years from now
あなたの教えは30年後を考慮しているのですね
I don't know who wrote the Taiwan professor's book
台湾の教授の本を誰が書いたのか知​​りません
Yes, so this very scary passage just now
はい、それでは今とても恐ろしい一節を
Dr. Xin Cai
シン・カイ博士
Thanks
ありがとう
i might want to chase at home
家で追いかけたいかも
But it's true
でも本当だよ
This is a study in Taiwan
これは台湾での研究です
then scientifically recognized
その後科学的に認められた
What would have to be rewritten would be a
書き直す必要があるのは、
things without origin
起源のないもの
But this is the pride of Taiwan
でもこれが台湾の誇りです
Taiwan's development
台湾の発展
Okay, wait a minute for everyone to see clearly
オーケー、みんながはっきり見えるまでちょっと待ってね
my second episode
私の2番目のエピソード
if not
そうでない場合
are we here to applaud
私たちは拍手をしにここにいますか
Thanks
ありがとう
Thank you.
ありがとう。